[Music]
Hey,
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
All right, here we are. Welcome to the
Ask a Budget Show, episode 279. I hope
everyone's doing great, fantastic,
awesome.
Um, we're going to discuss geopolitics
today. It's a geopolitics only live
stream and it's going to be a super chat
live stream. So, let's see who all is
there on the live chat with us. I can
see Saga Torat Air Tuli engineer Apurva
Rayan who is preparing for J mains
Binitro
Supria Tupri Swami Jane Shashank Koshik
Jri Krishna Mystic SK J Shri Krishna
Suhas Reddi Britan Jay Kalita Shashank
Koshik once again a board soul Jade
Sihar good evening engineer Sagar Torat
Aayush Singh Ajinkawar from Mumbai Abir
Tuli Supria Topri again Negro Shivam
Singh aboard soul happy Janashtmi
degenerate states all right all right
all right all right all right all right
all right all right saga to sag to Rahul
Lakshmanan animals for laugh devotey
geopolitical dub in from Indor
who else do we have Vladimir Putin says
Jesam well Jashir back to you sir Sonia
Sha gravity kah savory set Vikash PJ
Makavin from Hawaii Ashna John Aninda
Bachar Gi Sasmith superhero
shanks Anura Ja Ketan Desai superhero
Vikash Ashna John Abin of Ngi
Miscellaneous Niha All right. Uh Shivas
Sai Vishal Gohill Hersh Nayan Chhatan
Aradya Suas Tushar SK
Snaps. Okay. Mega tasita upad
beneath Kamat Anand Singh Jikit
Hola amigos says Amit Kumar Amisha
Mishra good evening kaha gravity
navindry anonymous
air sugata saha from Singapore well good
evening ma'am Rahul love praal guru Ataj
Singh and so many other people like
Yagami Aditya Punit Kumar Arun Prasad
Jedikshit Bimmanyu Takur Rahana Nur and
so many else so many else so many other
people. All right. All right. All right.
Let's go. Uh let's get going with the
questions otherwise I'll be doing this
all day. Let's get going with the
questions. What questions do we have?
Let's go with the first question which
is by Katria Bal. What are your thoughts
on the sinking western economies?
New Zealand has got massive unemployment
problem and people keep losing their
jobs. the blame the blame is being put
on the crazy spending done during COVID.
Well, yeah, interesting that you
mentioned CO here. So, let's take the
example that you're mentioning. New
Zealand, small nation, right? Off the
southeast coast of Australia, right? Two
large islands. I mean, two islands
mainly, pretty small nation. What's the
economy of New Zealand like? What does
it depend on? Well, if I think of it, I
can think of agriculture
and and sheep. Yeah, sheep and
agriculture. And secondly, tourism.
Apart from that, what's the New Zealand
economy going to depend on? I'm not
really sure what what it's what else it
has, what other other components it has.
Uh, so there are these two things,
agriculture and tourism, including
animal agriculture. Now COVID, you had
all this crazy spending and you had all
these measures that essentially tourism
died out for a while in New Zealand
because of COVID. Um, and I suppose
there must have been a lower demand for
other products. So that would have
brought the economy down. I suppose it
went into a recession at least for some
time. I'm not sure what the current
situation is like. So that explains why
New Zealand's economy is not doing so
great. U maybe low productivity, maybe
other factors also may be there.
So that's that's the example of New
Zealand. Australia I suppose may be
doing better. I mean Australia is not
actually part of the west but yeah
politically it's part of the west. If
you look at nations like Germany etc.
Well we know what's what's going on
there. Um Germany historically has been
the economic engine that drives
manufacturing engine economic engine
that drives the European economy. And
for an economy to do well, you need a
copious amount of, you know, constant uh
energy, cheap energy. And when cheap
Russian gas stops flowing into Germany
and they shut down their nuclear
reactors, well, things are going to go
bad. So, multiple issues depending on
which nation we are talking about. COVID
was obviously a big factor in things
going down. I mean, for a while even
India's economy went went backwards
because of COVID, right? But we
restarted everything as soon as it was
possible. Western countries seem to have
made some changes permanent and they may
be doing some things that are not good
for them. For example, Germany shutting
down all its nuclear nuclear power
plants. I mean, why on earth would you
do that? Why? So, what you going to go
back to coal? I think that that's what
they've done. So, multiple reasons
depending on which economy we're talking
about. Um, and yeah, New Zealand
apparently has massive unemployment,
people losing their jobs. Well, that's
terrible. So, what can New Zealand do to
kickstart to rekickstart its economy? I
suppose they need to focus on tourism
more, attract more people into the
country, maybe find more buyers for
their agricultural produce and whatnot.
Yeah, that sort of thing they need to
do. Uh COVID was definitely a factor,
but I don't think every western economy
is sinking. Uh the US is doing okay. I
suppose I'm not sure about the UK.
Overall, they're okay. some of them and
some of them are not doing very well. I
don't think any any of them is really
sinking as such. I don't know how many
nations are in recession right now if
there are any. But overall, yeah, that's
that's the situation. I think the future
obviously is in the east. The future is
in Asia. It's in India and China and
other countries in the region. And
that's why, you know, the west is well
throwing whatever tantrums it is,
Trump's tariffs and whatnot.
Okay. SFC says, "Will this current
tariff war between the US and
essentially the rest of the entire world
eventually result in global recession?
If so, how badly will it affect India?"
So, will this cause a global recession?
I don't think it's going to cause a glo
global recession. It's going to cause a
lot of pain to nations that have
historically depended on, you know,
exporting to the US. Now the US is going
to impose these restrictions as at least
as long as Trump is around and maybe
those things may become a little
permanent if it if this continues for
long it's possible but it's going but
these policies that Trump is employing
they're going to force other countries
essentially the rest of the world to
look for alternatives beyond the US that
is what it's going to cause so a nation
like India will look at other markets a
nation like whoever else whichever
nations are have historically been
exporting goods to the US will have to
will be forced to look at alternative
markets. It's going to cause a
realignment, a reshaping of the global
economic order. I don't think it's
necessarily going to cause a global
recession. I think the chances of that
are low. Uh how badly will this affect
India? Well, I think uh it could lower
India's GDP growth for the next year by
0.2 to 0.4%. 4%. So the RBI I believe
had uh forecast that the Indian GDP will
grow at about 6.5% next year. So if it's
0.2% reduction, it'll instead of 6.5%
the growth growth will be 6.3%.
And if it's a 4% reduction, then well it
it could be
uh 6.1%. If Yep. So that sort of thing.
So it's it's definitely not trivial.
It's going to have an effect. it's not
going to be a good effect and yeah we're
going to have to take measures to take
all of this into consideration.
Okay. Rahul Lakshmandan says probability
of probability estimate of India and
China resolving border once and for all
taking advantage of the current
situation. The probability of that
happening is about 1%.
Okay, not going to happen. What it means
is it's it's incredibly unlikely to
happen. Why would a nation like China
give up such a big advantage it has?
It's much more powerful than India,
isn't it? Economically as well as
militarily.
And it has this so as the more powerful
nation, you are in a position to put a
nation that's weaker than you under
pressure, under multiple kinds of
pressure. And how do you do that? Well,
if you have this big long tremendous
massive undemarcated border, then you
can keep on claiming territory and keep
on testing the strength of the of the
adversary,
keep on attempting to salvize territory,
why would you give that up, right?
Unless you're getting something
significant in return,
what does China get in return? If it
agrees to demarcate the border, it gets
peace. Well, India has any way never
been a nation that's threatened to take
parts of Chinese occupied territory. We
have never threatened that we will
retake Tibet. I mean, liberate Tibet or
what Tibet or whatever. So, China
doesn't fear an Indian incursion. China
doesn't fear an Indian invasion. But it
wants India to keep fearing fearing a
military conflict with China. Right? So,
when you are in that position where you
have the advantage in that, why would
you give it up? So even if there there
is a better relationship between India
and China, China will not agree to
demarcate the border unless it is in
some very precarious position and it it
desperately needs India's support and
help and all that in that case it may do
that. Well, it's not in that situation
right now and it doesn't look like it's
going to be in that sort of situation
anytime soon.
So my probability estimate of India and
China resolving the border issue once
and for all is 1% over the next 365
days. Yeah. So what will happen? What's
the best thing best case? The best case
is see tomorrow Mr. Wangi is visiting
India. Okay. He's going to be here for
maybe he's going to be in Delhi for a
day or two. After that he's going to
Pakistan, Afghanistan, wherever he's
going. He has his Yes. So the thorough
visit. So this visit by Mr. Wangi who's
the foreign minister of China it's
obviously a precursor to Mr. Modi's
visit to China for the SEO summit the
that visit will be at the end of this
month uh 31st of August or somewhere
somewhere around that time you can look
it up so Mr. Wangi will be in Delhi to
lay the groundwork for a successful
visit for Mr. Modi in China. That's what
it is. And obviously there's going to be
a continuation of the hundreds of rounds
of negotiations about the border issue
and all that. That that's a neverending
merrygoround. Nothing ever comes out of
it. So that's where we are. What's the
best thing that that could happen? You
know, Mr. Modi will probably have a
pleasant visit to China. Maybe something
constructive may come out of it and
maybe uh China may try to engage India
economically and offer some offer some
kind of uh
offerings something like that you know
but beyond that I don't see anything
major coming out of it. So that's where
we are.
Okay. Aninda Bachari says very big fan.
Thank you sir. Thank you. Uh please give
your insights on the recent developments
between Russia and the US. Will Trump
punish India? Well, we're talking about
Russia and US. So, we'll keep India out
of it for a moment. Okay, I I'll talk
about India as well. So,
Russia and the US. So, a couple of days
ago, Mr. Trump uh hosted Mr. Putin in
Alaska.
Excuse me.
So, Mr. Mr. Trump hosted Mr. Putin in
Alaska. Mr. Putin arrived in Alaska and
it was a reasonably brief uh meeting
like 2 and a half 3 hours. That's the
amount of time the two leaders and their
entouragees had uh in face toface talks
behind closed doors.
And beyond the optics, the optics are
wonderful red carpet treatment and um
both the leaders uh traveling in Mr.
Trump's limusine and the fighter planes
and the B2 bomber, strategic bomber that
fly that flew over the head of Mr.
Putin.
All of that stuff. That's all the
optics. Mr. Trump's handshake in which
he pulls the other guy's hand towards
him and then pats the back of the hand.
All of that is nice, okay? It's all
symbolism, blah blah blah. I don't care
about that. Let's talk about the real
substance. What came out of it, right?
What was the minimum that Mr. Trump
expected? The minimum that Mr. Trump
expected was a ceasefire, even a
temporary ceasefire,
some kind of ceasefire. That's what
that's the least that he expected from
the visit. That's what he wanted from
Mr. Putin.
A ceasefire, Ukraine war, obviously,
right? Did he get that? He didn't get
that. He got nothing from Mr. Putin. He
got absolutely nothing. The two the two
sides were behind closed doors for about
2 and 1/2 hours. And the expressions
were very different after those two and
a half hours. Before the both the
leaders went in, both leaders were nice,
smiling and happy, good body language.
When both leaders come out, Mr. Putin is
good. Mr. Trump is a little deflated.
What what happened behind closed doors,
right? Mr. Trump did not get what he
wanted.
Um, so the least he wanted was a
ceasefire. Now, we don't know what what
happened, what demands Mr. Putin made,
what demands Mr. Trump made. But you
have to understand what position both
leaders are in. Who is in a position of
strength? Who's in a position of
weakness? We have to understand that.
Who's in a position of strength? There's
a war going on and the leader who has
who who is in possession who is in
occupation of the adversaries territory
is Mr. Putin. The war is going well for
Mr. Putin. Right. Ukraine isn't winning.
Ukraine is losing.
Ukraine doesn't control an inch of
Russian territory. Mr. Putin controls
about a between a fifth and a fourth of
Ukrainian territory and his armed forces
are doing well. Ukraine is being
decimated. Ukraine's economy is in
shambles. The moment foreign aid stops
to Ukraine, Ukraine will will collapse,
right? It's entirely entirely dependent
on foreign aid on Western aid. Its
population, its demography has has
collapsed. All the young men are gone.
That's the situation in Ukraine. Ukraine
is a western proxy, an American proxy
and Putin is doing well. So Mr. Putin is
in a position of strength and he is
happy to wait as long as it takes for
the war to be over. He is in no hurry
for the war to end. His economy is doing
well. His economy is actually growing
compared to the European economies that
are going down. Recession, not all but
at least some of them for some time were
in recession. If you compare the Russian
economy with the European economies, the
Russian economy is doing good. Then
what position is Mr. So Mr. Putin is in
a position of strength. What position is
Mr. Trump in he is waging this war of
tariffs in the entire world. He is not
popular anywhere right now. Trust me, I
think we can all agree on that.
The tariffs are going to start biting at
his own citizens because they the
American citizens are paying the
tariffs, not the foreign countries. It's
going to cause a backlash in the US.
Prices will go up, inflation will rise.
It's going to not going to be good time
for Mr. Trump. Apart from that, Mr.
Trump had made this promise. You as a
leader, as a politician, you've got to
keep promises that you make otherwise
people don't people don't forget that
Mr. Trump had made this promise that I
will end the Ukraine day Ukraine war on
the first day of my presidency. Well,
he's been trying for trying for that.
He's been attempting to do that but it's
dragging on and on and on.
So who's under pressure? Who is in a
position of weakness? Mr. Trump is in a
position of weakness.
So you have Mr. Putin who is in a
position of strength. He is confident.
He is not impressed by all the fancy
fancymancy stuff that Mr. Trump is
showing him the fighter planes and all
that. He doesn't care. Mr. Putin has his
own stuff. So M Mr. Putin is a position
of strength. Mr. Trump is in a position
of weakness. He is desperate to get at
least something out of this. He wants a
ceasefire desperately.
It's overdue by more than 6 months now
for Mr. Mr. Trump.
So who needs the ceasefire? Who needs
something? Mr. Trump. And Mr. Putin is
happy to wait as long as it takes for a
ceasefire. If we don't get good terms,
we will not have a ceasefire. Right? So
that was the dynamic first of all the
power dynamic and we don't know what
happened behind closed doors but but but
when we saw both leaders emerge Mr.
Trump looked deflated
Mr. Putin looked great and Mr. Mr. Putin
in his address to the media he made it
very clear what his nation's red lines
are that the European security
architecture has to take into account
Russia's red lines and Russia's security
interest national interests without that
Europe it won't it won't work right and
I don't know what address Mr. Trump gave
to the media I heard it but he had
nothing of substance to say so that is
the recent developments so Mr. Mr. Trump
got nothing nothing out of it. There
will most likely be more rounds of
negotiations possibly between the two
leaders. The next time it has to be in
Russia. It has to be in Russia. It has
to be in Moscow like Mr. Putin insisted
essentially, right? Publicly. Uh and
let's see how it goes. But Mr. Trump is
not getting what he wants. Yeah, he has
been rebuffed and uh very nicely. So
will Trump punish punish India? Well,
let him do that. Yeah, they has been
threatening 500% tariffs. I mean it was
Lindsay whatever uh
Senator Lindsey Graham who has
threatened this who has brought in this
this this bill that would punish nations
that buy Russian oil with 500% tariffs
you know after a point the tariffs don't
matter anymore make it 3 million% right
who we don't care anymore we're done so
uh that's the situation will Trump
punish India maybe he will raise tariffs
to 70% maybe 100% maybe 150% % maybe to
500%. After a point it doesn't matter.
It's possible this may happen. Yeah,
they have canled the the visit of the US
trade delegation to India which was
supposed to come soon.
Okay, so be it. Right.
So that's where we are and we are
purchasing more Russian oil apparently.
Yeah. So that is the current situation
and we'll have to keep an eye on this.
We'll have to wait and watch and see how
it goes. I expect that India US
relations are fried for some time for
the for the longest time now.
Chandra, well thank you so much. Welcome
to the membership. Thank you so much.
Appreciate that.
Pawa says, "How does China see the
Alaska visit? Does has China lost
leverage on on Russia?" Well, the this
visit by Mr. Putin was well great for
Russia. Yeah, it's it was great for
Russia and uh the the whole world will
see Russia as a much more powerful
entity today after the meeting after the
outcome of the meeting which was clearly
one zero Putin won Trump zero clearly.
Uh
does this mean that China has lost its
leverage on Russia? No, it doesn't mean
that Russia will feel better. Russia
will be more confident. Trump will be
more desperate after this. They will be
looking for someone to lash out at,
somebody to blame. Maybe it's Zalinsky.
Maybe it's India. maybe whoever. Yeah.
Uh but China has not lost its leverage
on Russia because Russia is still under
all these sanctions and the US has
excluded Russia, cut Russia off from the
international economic system and so on.
So Russia is still very dependent on
China in a variety of ways. So China
hasn't lost that leverage but we'll see.
Yeah. If Russia can get a deal from the
US or if Trump can get a deal can
negotiate a deal with the Sabbutin which
is beneficial for both sides then yeah
then China will lose some leverage. If
that happens and Mr. Putin, Mr. Trump
will be cognizant of that perhaps if he
yeah looks at it that from that
perspective and maybe he doesn't want
Putin to to you know lose his dependence
on China. So it's it's complicated but
as of now China has not lost its
leverage on Russia.
Okay. What this video WTV says how does
a currency work? Can we use gold reserve
as a reference? Okay.
How does a currency work? A currency is
a substitute for something valuable.
That's what it's a proxy. A currency is
a proxy for something of value. So in
the past, there used to be the Bart
system. Like thousands of years ago, I
have two carrots. I want your apple. Two
carrots I say is equal to one apple. But
you say no, one apple should be three
carats. And so so there's a negotiation.
Maybe I will I will give you one carrot
and I'll take 1/4 of your apple. That
sort of thing. Or you know I have a
handful of wheat. What can you offer me?
Okay. I I'll give you a handful of
wheat. You give me a cup of of ghee.
Yeah. That sort of thing. So it used to
be this rough reference system long long
ago, thousands of years ago. Then
people started issuing coins.
coins. Coins usually were made of gold.
If you look at ancient Indian coins,
most of these are gold coins uh small
coins, big big coins, whatever size. And
gold obviously is an extremely rare
commodity. So, it is very valuable.
So, so kings start in and emperors and
dynasties and empires started issuing
coins of specific denominations,
specific sizes with a specific amount of
gold. and the gold itself was was
valuable. Uh so the coins began to be
used as a substitute for for the barter
system. So a coin would be determined by
the market to have a certain value.
Let's say I have a gold coin. Maybe I
can buy 20 cows with that. Yeah. Or
maybe I can buy a certain amount of land
with that or or whatever it was. So
that's how a currency started working.
Eventually in the in in in in the west
in Europe they started issuing paper
currencies. Paper currencies were a
substitute for gold on which on those
paper currencies it it was written that
this is to be used in exchange for gold
and when the bearer of this of this note
demands a certain amount of gold equal
to this it has to be provided on demand.
Right? So it was then easier to car
carry around than gold. So then people
started but but the issuer of that paper
currency I I suppose was legally bound
to have that much the amount of currency
they've issued that much gold they
should have
only then would a bank or or or an
issuer of currency be trusted by the
consumers so that's how a currency works
and then eventually in the 21st 20th
century the US uh so when the US dollar
became the reserve currency of the world
it was pegged to the price of gold and
the US was supposed to have that much
gold in storage equal to the amount of
currency was US dollar currency was in
circulation globally.
But in the 70s I think it was Nixon
Nixon and Kissinger Nixon who decoupled
the US dollar the paper from the gold.
It was now free floating. It was not
dependent on the amount of gold because
of a bank run on the US. That's a whole
different story. We'll not go into the
history. and and today the US currency
is I don't know what it represents. It's
it's it's a fiat currency. It's a
currency that represents the power of
the US to enforce the US dollar as the
world reserve currency. So you know
that's how a currency works. Can we use
gold reserve as a reference? Well the
Indian rupee is also I don't think it's
tied to the price of gold. Uh but it
would be ideally good if currencies were
tied to the to to a certain amount of to
the price of gold. That would be a
that's a that's a more robust currency I
would say.
Amisha says, "Do you really do you
really think that Trump can stop
the Ukraine Russia war?" It doesn't look
like that. It doesn't look like that. If
I mean, he's been desperate to do it,
right? But so many factors are are
conspiring to come in his way. First of
all, Putin is in no hurry to end the
war. Why why should he? You people
started this. He will tell the west you
people started this you did not respect
our red lines and then eventually you
encroached into into Ukraine itself
right that's why we had to we we we had
to take first of all Crimea and then you
did it further by you know by various
means and that's why the war started now
I am in no hurry to end the war I am
doing very well Russia is doing very
well right so if you want an end to the
war it has to be on my terms I'm going
to demand I'm going to make maximalist
demands
you either do what I say or the war
continues
and well the west may be tempted perhaps
to stop funding the war because it's a
you're burning your money but then
Ukraine the whole of Ukraine goes so
that's the tight spot that the west is
in and Zelinsky who is propped up by the
EU
well if the war ends what happens to him
so he's desperate for the war not to end
so all of these factors are coming in
the way to to you know prevent the war
from ending so I don't think that Trump
is Trump is in any position unless he
does something about Zilinsky to end the
war. Yeah.
Hersh Nyan says
one thing India has to be careful about
China is based on previous patterns they
have always tried to be aggressive
whenever its thing doing good which
thing good doing good. So, China has
historically been a very aggressive
nation. We know that. Um, 19662 is a
good example. 2020, the g the Galwan
clash. Well, that was perhaps
accidental. Perhaps they tried to push
too far, but they they yeah, they got a
bloody nose. See, the Galwan clash
is is not something that's comparable to
the 1962 war or the 1967 war. No one
knows about 1967, right? which we won or
the 1988 87 clashes. The Galwan thing
was much more oneoff and much more
localized. But China has always been
this hegemonic nation,
right? Ever since the Chinese Communist
Party came to power, they have always
been this hgemonic nation. In the past
also, they've always tried to bully
weaker nations going back 2,000 years.
Right? So, we have to be careful about
China. the and what China respects is
strength and what what they what
and if you are weak they're going to
take advantage of that. So I agree with
you sir. We have to be careful about
China. You can never trust a nation that
uh with whom you have this sort of
history. Uh you have to understand what
kind of uh behavioral patterns they have
ex exhibited in the future. Even if
there is a even if there is a rapimo
with China and things are good in the
future let's say still India will always
have to be super careful when dealing
with China.
So I agree. Yes sir.
Rohan Sunija says, "How can Russia be
more stronger be stronger militarily
than China despite having a smaller
economy than China as per my power
index? Please explain."
Okay. Uh the economy is smaller. Um see
the power index that I have it's based
on
publicly available information.
Completely public information. No hidden
variables.
So what kind of publicly available
information do we have? What what data
what numbers do we have that that can
define a country represent a country?
First is your land area. Your land area
is a big factor in your power because
that is the amount of resources that you
have at your disposal. Secondly,
population. The more your population,
the more resources, you know, manpower,
human capital. That is two things very
simple that everybody understands. Then
the size of your economy, which is your
GDP, annual GDP. Let's take that as an
indicator of the size of your economy
and the strength of your economy, annual
GDP. Then your annual military uh
expenditure. So you always take the
latest figures. Well, the latest figures
is are that you know Russia Russia's
military expenditure annually is in
excess of hundred billion dollars now.
It's so gone way past India and other
nations. So it's the third largest
military spend uh it's got the third
largest military spending in the world,
Russia. So that's another factor. Then
you look at things like power projection
uh capabilities which is kind of it's
it's more of an art than a science to
calculate that. But yeah, it's certainly
something that matters. And then the
number of nuclear warheads that you
have. So you take all of this together,
you calculate a score based on a
formula, which is my formula. Well, and
and that applies to all nations. Russia
clearly comes out on top. I mean the
major the major differentiator
is the number of nuclear weapons and I
am not basing the nuclear number of
nuclear weapons on my imag imagination.
I'm just taking what is the publicly
available figures out there the best
accepted figures which says India has
what 160 or whatever so and China has
600 and Russia has the world's largest
nuclear arsenal. Well, that itself makes
Russia invincible, the nuclear arsenal,
right? Because nobody will dare to mess
with Russia. Do you understand? So, if
you take all the factors together and
you calculate the score, well, Russia
turns out to be stronger. Now, that's
the best I can explain.
Okay. Tanahesh Pande says Pakistani
media said that they lost 155 soldiers
during Operation Synindu. Yes, the
three-day war, but then they deleted the
the article. Yeah, it's been deleted. I
mean, so do you think another battle
took place take place after Munir's
threat? Okay, let's deal with the issue
of the 155 soldiers.
So
recently like two or three days ago the
Pakistani military announced that they
had given various uh gallantry awards
and whatever awards to their uh to their
personnel military personnel
based on their performance in their
operation bunan manhus whatever it was.
Yeah. Uh which is operation synindur.
And they put out a list of all the
soldiers who were given these awards.
And in that list of soldiers, you had
155 deceased soldiers. Soldiers who died
in operation.
Right. So they they published the entire
list nicely, properly. Very nicely. Very
nicely. Yes. Nicely. And then the Indian
well India's India has this gigantic
population and people are very active on
social media. So Indians caught it and
they took screenshots and pasted it all
all over social media. So then the
Pakistanis realized that we are
admitting what happened. We are
admitting that we lost 155 soldiers. So
they hastily deleted that article but
while the screenshots will live forever.
So yep it's clear that Pakistan you know
it suffered tremendous casualties. 155
soldiers that's well that's the ones who
have got those gallantry awards. I don't
know how many else how many other
soldiers there could have been that that
may have died. We don't know that for
sure. Um
so yeah that's that's the deal. They
admitted it then they realized what they
did so they deleted that. Now do I think
another battle will take place after
Munir's threat? Well I think there's a
there's a chance that there could be a
new India Pakistan war soon. The US is
is backing up Pakistan Pakistan to the
hilt. Trump is backing Pakistan to the
hilt. Right.
And it looks like the west is now taking
the US is now taking the containment of
India very seriously. They don't want
India to become a 10 trillion economy.
Forget about 20 15 20 whatever. They
don't want India to reach the 10
trillion economy mark. That's why these
sanctions I mean not sanctions tariffs
on India and all the hostile behavior
from Trump and Trump backing Pakistan
thoroughly clearly taking Pakistan's
aside against India. Um and now the
Pakistanis have some idea of of their of
their strategic and and tactical
military weaknesses against India. They
took a thorough beating against India.
So they would have done a proper
assessment and given a laundry list of
things they they want to the US and the
US will try and supply Pakistan with
whatever Pakistan needs to to ensure a
favorable outcome in the next war. So
it's very likely that the US will supply
Pakistan with what whatever uh whatever
Pakistan was missing during operation
zindur. Uh and the longer we go without
a war with Pakistan the stronger
Pakistan will get.
So I think it's it's possible I think
it's likely that in the coming months or
or you know not of in the in the
short-term future maybe next 12 months
there could be another war instigated by
by a larger power between India and
Pakistan the objective is to weaken
India militarily and to weaken India
economically especially economically
India's economy is the only major
economy that is well that has no chance
of recession next 20 years and if that
continues India's economy will No matter
what kind of tariffs Trump Trump
imposes, India's economy will do well
and will grow and we will become more
powerful. So the best way to damage a
nation's economy is to is to drag it
into a prolonged conflict, a Ukraine
kind of situation,
right? And for India, the best Ukraine
is Pakistan. So it's it's I think likely
that there could be in the in the
short-term future another conflict with
Pakistan.
Saita Read says key agreements between
Trump and Putin. Any guess? Zero.
Zero agreements. If there was any
agreement, even a shred of an agreement,
Trump would have shouted it from the
rooftops.
rooftops and he would have said, "See,
this is one more feather in my cap. Now
I definitely need no Nobel Peace Prize."
He's desperate for a Nobel Peace Prize.
He's craving a Nobel Peace Prize, right?
So he wants more examples to bolster
more more achievements to bolster his
his claim on a Nobel Peace Prize. If
there was anything that came out of the
meeting which would have been favor
favorable to the US, he would have been
shouting it from the rooftops.
Absolutely nothing happened.
Okay. Pall says should India build an
alliance with Cyprus, Armenia and Greece
to counter Pakistan, Azarbaijan, Turkey.
Well, we are already doing that by the
way. We are already doing that. Uh, Mr.
Modi recently visited Cypress.
I'm talking about southern southern
Cypress. Free Cypress, not the northern
part which is Turkish occupied Cypress.
Would you like to see? Let's let's open
the map. It's been 37 minutes. We
haven't opened the map. So, let's go.
Let's take a look at Cypress.
So, Cypress, it is located in the
Mediterranean, the Eastern
Mediterranean.
Okay,
this is the island of Cypress. It's
historically always been a Greek island.
In the 1970s, Turkey
uh invaded Cyprus and occupied the
northern third of the land. And as you
can see, there are these dashed lines
and there's this no man's zone, no man's
land kind of thing. Yeah. Uh
so yeah, and and the capital city
Nikicoia itself is divided into a
southern part and a northern part. Uh so
Cyprus is under Turkish occupation and
Turkey as we know is is a great
supporter of Azarbaijan and they these
two nations together want to uh erase
Armenia from the map of the world.
Armenia is a nation with whom we've had
ancient ties. Uh and Turkey is is a
major supporter of Pakistan in a variety
of ways. So India we know that we have
military cooperation significant
military cooperation with Greece that's
been going on for quite some time I mean
couple of years at least you know
serious military cooperation India is
one of one of the the nations that
supplies arms to Armenia very dangerous
very powerful weapons right we have been
supplying to Armenia and now Mr. Modi
recently visited Cyprus and it was it
was by all accounts an excellent meeting
and so what India is doing is India is
is essentially creating an alliance with
Cypress, Armenia and Greece. So what
you're suggesting well we are already
doing that but it's a great suggestion
and I have to commend you on that. So
yeah it's an anti-Turkey alliance
that's what it is and we are doing that.
Geopolitical Dub says does climate
affect geopolitics if it does how? Well,
look,
climate can affect geopolitics only if
it changes very rapidly. Otherwise,
climate is like a constant factor.
Africa, northern Africa, temperate.
The Sahara part of Africa, the Sahel
region hot and dry. Uh Kalahari desert
hot. Southern Africa cool. That's we
know that the coastal regions so and so
the interior parts of Africa the
tropical rainforests tropical uh climate
if you talk about India depending on
where you are in India we know the what
the climate is so if you are let's say
going to do a military expedition or
operation somewhere in the part in
whatever part of the world you have to
know exactly what the climatic patterns
are and that does affect the kind of uh
military operation and and military
strategies and tactics you can employ
and beyond the military realm If you
just talk about the economic realm,
well, climate affects the nation's
economy obviously um based on what
resources you have in the climate, you
know, your economy can take various
shapes and forms and that of course
affects the nation's politics, the
nation's culture. So, climate has a
profound effect on the evolution of
history, right? So, it does affect
history and ge and what is history? What
we call history is was once the
geopolitics of that time and the
geopolitics of today is tomorrow's
history. So climate does indeed affect
geopolitics.
Vishall says if peace talks fail will
breach Russian red lines well they can't
afford to.
They can't afford to otherwise they risk
nuclear war right. Russia has very clear
red lines and Russia's nuclear doctrine
has changed a bit in the preceding
couple of years two three years and it's
become a little more ambiguous than
before
and u yeah so if this if they cross
certain lines they and and you know
actually they they did cross some
Russian red lines that that what's an
operation operation spiderweb that
Ukraine undertook carrying out long
range strikes on Russian strategic
assets deep inside Russia that actually
did cross that it did breach some red
lines but the major red lines if the US
breaches even if peace talks fail if you
breach those red lines you're inviting a
tremendous amount of trouble I don't
think the US dares do that
satellite says why are India Russia ties
always strong will they remain so are
India and Russia the most reliable
long-term partners among major countries
if yes why so historically if you look
at the overall trajectory of the ties
it's been pretty good. I mean the
strongest partner India has had
essentially. Yeah. For various reasons.
So in in the 20th century India decided
to become Soviet Wasal essentially.
Right. Technically we were non-aligned.
I know some geniuses will come and now
lecture me that what non what was we
were non-aligned.
If all you do is read your history
textbooks and listen to what your
teachers say then you will never learn a
thing. India was basically a Soviet
satellite.
in the 20th century.
Uh and because of that that's why the US
decided to make Pakistan their vasal
right and strengthen that relationship.
Uh but the kind of vasal relationship
the US has with its vasals is very
damaging long in the long run to those
vasals when the USSR and the Russia has
they that relationship isn't that
damaging. Obviously they will spy on the
nation and do things etc. But they don't
damage they don't try to change the
culture they don't try to change the
various aspects of of governance and so
so on in the in the vasal countries so
for some time India was a soviet vasal
okay
um but the USSR supplied India with
excellent weapons I mean the Mig 21 when
it was supplied to India was the
deadliest fighter aircraft in existence
okay and the Mig 25 is it Foxbat what I
mean they supplied the best weapons
happens to India and they never laid
down conditions and inserted kill
switches and back doors and whatn not
the kind of things the Americans do and
when India needed Soviet help in 1971
the Soviets came to India's help and
that's why Bangladesh was created
so it's been a relationship that's been
very robust it's a trusting relationship
we India and Russia understand each
other very well because of the long
duration of the relationship trip uh
when the USSR collapsed and broke up in
the early 1990s 1999 ' 91 that's when
India found itself a drift Indian
politicians were used to having a big
daddy now what do we do so that's why
India started looking at the west yeah
because of the Anglo anglicized nature
of the Indian elites and all that um so
for some time the relationship was
essentially non-existent it was it was
not great uh the Soviets, the Russians
caved into American pressure and
declined to sell uh cryogenic engines,
rocket engines to India um or or and
transfer the techn technology as was as
was the agreement and so on. But things
stabilized after Mr. Putin came to power
and the relationship was again decent.
Now if you remember in the in the 2010s
around 2015 or so around that time the
Russians sold military equipment to
Pakistan helicopters and all and they
they had these annual exercises between
you know military exercises between
Russia and Pakistan. The dujba exercises
what does dujba mean in Russian? It
means friendship. So we have to remember
these things. We have to remember look
no relationship is is set in stone. If
India becomes irrelevant if India tilts
very far westwards then Russia will stop
regarding India as a valuable partner.
If Russia starts playing games with
Pakistan then India will stop regarding
Russia as a valuable partner. I think
there's a tremendous amount of potential
in the relationship and uh as we know
the the US doesn't the US has this now
very clear policy of containing India if
you look if you look at all the US
actions in the past three years only
just the past 3 years 3 years yeah the
coup against Imran Khan yeah so regime
change operation in Pakistan and
Pakistan once again becomes West
Pakistan once again becomes a US vasal
then the regime change in in Bangladesh
so east Pakistan becomes a US vasal then
project K cookie land for Christ which
is an you know an attempt to to it's
it's a challenge to Indian sovereignty
essentially in Manipur and so much more
so if you look at all these actions the
US has taken they they're aimed at
containing India and destabilizing India
right and the same thing is being done
to Russia so because of that shared
issue also India and Russia uh obviously
are are on a very um convergent uh
trajectory right now. So overall India
and Russia have see major nations no
territorial disputes no major disputes
of any kind. So natural partners India
and Russia are natural partners and uh I
expect this to continue uh despite
whatever small hiccups may happen here
and there here or there those may be
temporary right so right now we are
hearing rumors that Mr. Putin may not
visit India as planned in by the end of
this year. It's it's a possibility. But
if if that's the case, it may be a
temporary thing because of various
external factors. If that does happen,
uh most likely he will visit, but we'll
see. Uh so overall, I I I see this as a
very promising, very robust long-term
relationship. India and Russia are
natural partners unlike Russia and China
or or India and China which are natural
adversaries.
Okay.
MK says, "In what ways are the US and
the British Empire similar and
different? Did the US make any serious
attempts to make France its vasal like
it did to the US Irish protest?" Ah, you
Oh, you you've been paying attention,
have you, sir?
Look, the Irish troubles is something
that the UK created itself. Okay.
Ireland is under you under British
occupation and that's why you had
troubles in Northern Ireland for decades
for decades all the way from the
beginning of the 20th century because
Ireland is is under British occupation.
They want to be free from the British.
They have never liked the British. The
British are foreigners for the Irish.
Right. So the troubles
the the root cause of the troubles was
British actions themselves.
But it's it's very interesting like I've
said before that the Northern Ireland
insurgency ended just like that the
moment Tony Blair became a made the UK
an American vasal. Very interesting.
Very interesting. Is it a coincidence?
Really? Really? Uh so yeah. So the UK
becomes a US vasal and the Irish
troubles end just like that. No issues.
All peaceful now. But I'll tell you that
undercurrent still simmers. The people
of Northern Northern Ireland are still
under British occupation. It's British
occupied Northern Ireland. Now coming to
your question, has the US made serious
attempts to make France its vasal?
France is a quasi of the US. It is it is
France is a member of NATO.
Who owns NATO? It's the US that owns
NATO by the way. Okay. Oh, technically
it's a multilateral logger. Blah blah
blah. Okay, go back to the third
standard if if that's that's how you see
it.
The US owns NATO. France is a member of
NATO. If you are a member of NATO, you
lose military sovereignty. You lose
sovereignty over your armed forces.
Because if you are a member of NATO, you
have to put your armed forces at times
under foreign command under the command
of a foreign foreigner.
Yeah.
at least some portion of your armed
forces at any given point in time are
under the command of a foreigner if
you're a member of NATO. So there you
lose your military sovereignty.
Secondly, the the French are also a me
are also members of the EU. Who owns the
EU? It's once again the US. If you are a
member of the EU, you don't have your
own currency. You have to use the EU
currency. So you lose economic
sovereignty. Secondly, your borders are
open. You've lost your territorial
sovereignty. These are the hallmarks of
a vasal nation. The only thing France
has going for itself is um the nuclear
deterrent which is entirely French and
and other things as well. That's why
France has a quasi independent foreign
policy and is less of a vasal than let's
say Germany or any other EU or NATO
nation. The most quasi independent of
the nations is France but it is still a
US vasal. Okay.
So yeah, how are the US and British
Empire similar yet different? Very
similar, very similar. But um the the US
doesn't occupy other nations militarily
except for a couple of cases. One case
is Japan, another is South Korea and and
Germany and Italy are also under some
form of US occupation since 1945. But
the British colonized extractively. See
the British uh engaged in extractive
colonization whether it's India which
was the major target of extractive
colonization or African nations or
wherever else the US isn't uh doesn't
employ extractive colonization it it is
a hegemonic empire not not an
occupational empire not an empire of
occupation and it extracts value from
the world through its reserve currency
which is the US dollar. So they are they
are similar and different in in a
variety of ways but overall very similar
same culture same Anglo culture and the
US empire is an extension it's a
continuation of the British Empire.
Okay. Verun Baj says
what would India be like today if India
hadn't lost territories like Pakistan
and Bangladesh to British wouldn't
partition also where Afghanistan,
Myanmar, Sri Lanka part of India before
the British? This is a history question
not geopolitics question but let's just
briefly answer it. See I would request
you all that please look at the pinned
comment.
We are discussing geopolitics today. If
I start taking questions about other
topics today then well it's
disrespecting the audience right?
What would India be like today if we had
not lost those territories? We would be
a more multi-religious nation. Maybe we
would be stronger if we had strong
leaders right. Um Afghanistan was
Gandhar obviously part of India Myanmar
it's questionable during the British Raj
Myanmar was part of India it was always
part of the Indosphere but was it part
of Jamudi probably not I may be wrong
but I don't see it that way Sri Lanka
well Sri Lanka was always part of India
overall
okay always different kingdoms in Sri
Lanka but
Sri Lanka was part of the Chola Empire
for example and it was also part of the
Gupta empire. So two presidents over
there. Naman Singh says why don't our
people support Indian products and apps?
Make a world-class product. Make world
worldass apps that are better than
everything the others have to offer.
People will automatically gravitate
towards that.
I'll give you an example. We have an
Indian version of Twitter called Coup,
right? I tried using it. It was super
buggy. It was so hard to use. It was a
it was a pain to use it. You want an app
that's a pleasure to use. If Indians
make substandard apps and then they say
that Indians should support Indian apps,
well, it's it's not going to work that
way. The market has its own dynamics,
right?
So, if it it I I agree that Indians
should support Indian Indian products
and Indian apps. But very often for for
example, there was there was this
product called Micromax. They used to
make phones. there were Chinese
manufactured phones with an Indian brand
put on them. So Indians take these
shortcuts, Indians haven't invested in
research and development and creating a
proper ecosystem and and products that
are world class. So once India starts
producing products that are world class
and we are fully capable of that. Look
at our defense equipment which we
manufacture worldass better than world
class. We have all of this. But the
people who have money, the the the the
industrialists,
well, they they need to change their
attitude and approach and and of course
startup people who are in startups who
are manufacturing stuff, they need to
manufacture worldclass products. The
moment you have something that nobody in
the world has of that, if you have
something of that quality, obviously
everybody will buy it. So don't force
Indians to buy substandard products
because they are Indian. Make the best
product products in the world or even
decent products. Then many Indians will
just buy the decent product even if
something slightly superior exists
elsewhere because it's Indian. But don't
manufacture bad products. That's what I
would say.
Okay.
uh as per mathematics and physics how
does a range is how do you estimate the
range of an ICBM uh test okay how
there's an ICBM test and how do you
estimate the range well I'll tell you
how mathematics okay uh and physics so
let us go to the map
okay here we have map yes we can see map
so where is the place in in Odisa Odisha
that's this this island right from which
we launched launch u
is this the island not ka okay this one
Abdul Kalam island uh typically you
launch missiles from there and do rocket
test from there so let's say you launch
something from here we put a marker here
Abdul Kalam Island and uh we do an ICBM
test or some kind of test and we so
before the government of India does a
test it uh issues a notice notice to
airmen nam Okay. Um and it says that no
aircraft should fly in a certain part of
the Indian Ocean region uh for on so and
so date for so and so time maybe 6 hours
maybe 3 hours whatever it is uh and that
gives you an indication of the range of
the test. So let's say we we have
something so we have an upcoming test
which will which is going to splash down
somewhere here about 4.8 8 or 5,000 km.
I'm not sure if it's that long. Maybe it
is low less than that. Around 4,000
something kilometers is the the current
no time that we have issued.
Um so it would be an indicator that the
Indian government military is expecting
the missile to have at least you know
maximum range of this much. So that
tells you that the missile has a maximum
range of 4,300 something km. If if
that's the range maybe we've given a no
time of 5,000 km then we would estimate
that the maximum range of this missile
as as calculated
incorporating safety measures by the
government and the military is 5,000 km.
So that's just a straightforward
assessment of what the range could be.
But now now understand this.
See missiles can be used in a variety of
ways.
A missile a ballistic missile it it It
it has a parabolic
bra. It has a parabolic path. Standard
projectile motion which you will learn
in your eighth standard or whatever
physics parabolic path. It will take
off. It will exit the atmosphere then
re-enter the atmosphere and hit the
target at re-entry speeds which is about
20 km/ second per hour second. Yeah,
around that that sort of speed 20 25 km/
second.
Now what sort of parabola is it? Is it a
flat parabola? If it is a very flat
parabola, it'll never exit the
atmosphere. If it's a very loopy
parabola, it will go kilo like hundreds
of kilometers above atmosphere and
return. Well, that tells you what kind
of range it has. So,
so the range that you the notam tells
you is an is is is an approximate range.
It's not really a true indicator of the
range of the missile. So India generally
what it does what India generally does
is it
under reportports the range of its
missiles. So let's say we are doing a
test of a missile and our no time is
5,500 km.
So one could estimate that this missile
is a 5,000 km range. But maybe we don't
want to show the world what the real
range is. So we are
creating a variant of the missile with
less fuel. Maybe the actual range is
13,000 km, but we we only put enough
fuel in the missile
for 5,500 km. So that way you don't you
don't alarm certain nations who would
then become the potential recipients of
a package. Yeah. Uh that that is the
thing. So I think India has very smartly
done done this been very smart about
this. We always under report we
generally under reportport the true
range of the of the missiles. so as to
not alarm certain nations who anyway
want to be alarmed and so on. Uh so
that's how we do it.
Ankita says why was Alaska chosen for
the Trump Putin meeting? Yes, why was
Alaska? Now first of all do we know
where Alaska is? Let us quickly uh visit
Alaska and see where it is. So we go
north of India straight north. We cross
Mongolia and we come to Russia. Okay,
this is Russia. This is Russia. Now you
go eastwards, eastwards, eastwards. Then
you have the Kamchchatka peninsula. You
go further eastwards, further eastwards
and you have
you have the bearing straight and you
have two Damedi islands here.
Little Diamedi is owned by the US and
big Damed is owned by Russia and between
I mean the two two islands are about 40
I don't know 4 km apart. Four yeah 4
kilometers apart as you can see here. So
that's the distance between Russia and
the US. And I once had a comment a few
years ago from a lady who live whose
family was from one of these two
islands. Yeah. Uh so that's the bearing
straight. And if you go further east
from the bearing state straight, you
reach Alaska. This is America's
northernmost state. Straight lines as
you can see. That's the consequence of
colonialism. Colonization. And yeah, so
this is the n the the state of Alaska,
America's northernmost state state. And
this was once a Russian territory. It
was a Russian territory and it was sold
to the US for a certain amount of money.
The Americans bought it and at that time
it was considered by many Americans to
be completely stupid that America bought
this big territory from Russia by paying
a lot of money. But today it turns out
it was a very valuable purchase and a
very cheap purchase because Alaska is
full of oil and gas and all kinds of
resources.
So it's a it's a territory that was
formerly Russian.
It still has possibly some Russian
influence
culturally, religiously, whatever. And
it's now an American territory and it
was acquired by America legally from
Russia. Right? So that's the shared
history of Alaska between the two
between the two nations. So why was
Alaska chosen for the Trump Putin
meeting? Because it is something that
both nations at some point in time had
in common. It's also an example of uh a
transfer of territory that that happened
legally without the use of force. So
maybe Trump wanted to remind Mr. Putin
that you know if you want territory you
have to take it legally without using
force. Uh so it's it's a region that has
multiple layers of meaning for both
nations. Uh some people in Russia today
may ru the fact that they sold Alaska to
the US. They would have wanted to
perhaps, you know, some people may
imagine it would be so nice if Russia
had this territory in northern North
America, right? Um so that's one one
layer of of symbolism. Secondly, uh from
the Americans, it's now American
territory but with a Russian influence,
Russian past. So if if both leaders meet
there and it's kind of equidistant in
some ways from the main land land masses
of both nations. So it has multiple
layers multiple layers of meaning. Uh so
it made sense for Alaska to be chosen. I
mean it's it's far in the north of North
America an almost desolate land very
nice very rich in resources and all very
small population. So yeah may people may
ask themselves why did this why was this
place chosen out of everything else why
not Washington why not Moscow why not
somewhere else but it's it's got this
very interesting history it's very
symbolic and that's why Alaska was
chosen
James says if India is so good why do
Indians come to the UK
yes why do Indians come to the UK you
see
today in West a lot of people complain a
lot of westerners complain why do these
hitty third world types why do they come
and pollute our land why do they come
and live in our lands stay in your third
world countries right why you why do you
if if your country your culture and
everything is so nice why do you come
and live in the west go back to your
countries you see it's not that simple
my dear James
you folk Folks, you know what you did?
You destroyed cultures. You destroyed
civilizations. You took the world's I'll
take the example of India. The world's
most prosperous
entity
nation wasn't a nation. It was a
kingdom, empire, whatever. You took this
place with a with the oldest
civilization that the world knows of and
you destroyed it. You did not come to
India for the sake of you know uplifting
the poor downrodden people of India
because they were so backward because we
were so poor. You did not come to do
social service.
Columbus why was he looking for India
for gold right? He stumbled upon
something else but that's that was the
intention. And why did the East India
Company come to the come to India? Why
was it formed?
It was a joint stock company wasn't it?
A lot of very rich people put money
together, created stock and they set up
the East India Company to trade with
India. Why?
Why? To become richer, to extract
something of value out of India.
Eventually, because of the political
situation in India at the time, no
political unity and so on, the East
India Company was able to take over
India gradually piece by piece and they
proceeded to destroy the country,
deindustrialize the country. India was
the world's first fully industrialized
civilization.
India accounted for a third of the
entire world's GDP.
And what and by the time the British
left, what happened? India accounted for
less than 2% of the world's GDP. What
happened? The British systematically
de-industrialized India. The British
systematically starved India. The
British systematically
conducted genocide. They imposed their
language, their education system, their
religion. They tried to destroy
everything that India had. And by the
time the British left, India's life
expectancy was 31 years. Imagine that.
That's what the British did. So these
Indians who had been enslaved by the
British for two and a half centuries.
They then acquired the slave mentality
that the white man is is best and the
white lands are best. And India was a
place of abject poverty. So they thought
okay let's let's migrate to the land of
the white man maybe we will have better
lives there. So you folks came and
destroyed everything and then and and
took all the wealth away
enriched yourselves. So then your place
become becomes a place of riches and
better lifestyle. So then people
obviously will try their best to to
leave the country you destroyed. So
that's why Indians come to the UK. Even
today India is suffering from the after
effects of British occupation two and a
half centuries. We are still suffering
from that. We are still trying to uh
stand up on our two feet. We were on our
knees for the longest time. We are now
standing up slowly gradually. It it
could be faster. Why is it not faster?
Because of all the corruption and decay
that you dumped into India. 1947 was a
transfer of power from one set of crooks
to another set of crooks. Your
handpicked crooks. And that's why the
system in India was so bad. That's why
you had Fabian socialism in India for
decades
and so much more. I could go on my
friend. India used to be good good.
India was the greatest civilization of
all. You folks destroyed it
and that's why Indians come to the UK
and Pakistanis
and Bangladeshies.
It's called karma and you are paying the
price for that. I wish you all the best
sir. I mean what I what I mean is I wish
you karma.
May you pay the price.
Punch says
operation zind 100 days day analysis
please. It boosted Bat's morale and
deterred Pakistan but they did they did
give China a weapons test lab and signal
India as a US adversary. Overall net
positive thoughts.
Okay. Last last question is did it
signal India as a US adversary? No.
India was taking steps for self-defense.
Whatever India did was in self-defense,
right? If Pakistan has a terror factory
next door which is pushing in terrorists
and killing Indians, we've got to do
something about that. It's called
self-defense. That doesn't make India a
US adversary. But if if the US chooses
to to to side with Pakistan, that's then
the US is positioning itself as as an
Indian adversary.
India attacking terror camps in Pakistan
doesn't make India a US adversary. But
we have to remember that the US has the
track record of funding and financing
Pakistani terrorism since at least
essentially Christmas Day 1979 rights
bin Laden used to fight on the west. He
was he was a western creation.
Yeah. So it's the US that has chosen to
support Pakistan and thereby make India
an adversary thereby designate India as
an as an adversary implicitly right so
there you have that now 100 days
analysis has it been yeah it's been
three 3 months plus so yeah it did boost
Bat's morale it did hammer Pakistan but
it did not destroy Pakistan Pakistan
still exists and now Trump is is is
supporting Pakistan he's investing in
Pakistan. He is going to do his best to
make Pakistan a very prosperous nation.
Apparently, that's what Aim is promising
the people of Pakistan, the the
Pakistani dictator, Aim Mun. So, Trump
is going to invest in Pakistan's
so-called oil and gas sector. Trump is
investing in uh Pakistan's uh rare
earths minerals sector. Trump is
investing in Pakistan's cryptocurrency
market. And since Trump is so invested
in Pakistan, it's possible that the
whatever deficiencies Pakistan's
military may have, those may be covered
up as soon as possible by the US
possibly. Maybe they will sell weapons
to Pakistan. Who knows? We'll see about
that. Um,
so that's the situation. So the US is
positioning India as an adversary now or
they are positioning themselves as an
Indian adversary. We haven't done a
thing.
It's their choice. It's America's choice
whatever they are doing. Um, did
Operation Synindur give China a weapons
test lab? Well, the Chinese weapons that
were tested in Operation Synindur, which
which they were, were export versions of
Chinese weapons.
Those weren't the actual weapons that
Chinese military uses. So, there are two
grades of weapons. Okay? If you are a
weapons exporter, you will manufacture
weapons for your own own armed forces,
which will be the best possible. But you
will also put those weapons on the on
the on the international market for
whoever wants to buy them. And if there
is a buyer, you're going to export
something called an export version which
is a slightly less capable version. So
that if that weapon systems if that
weapons system falls into the hands of
somebody who is enimical to you, they
will not be able to reverse engineer the
full technology and understand your
actual technological progress. So you
give export versions. So the P so the
Chinese so the Pakistanis used Chinese
radars, they used Chinese missiles
um and and whatever else and those and
and Chinese JF7 fighter planes. Well,
clearly the Chinese weapons didn't do
well. That's that's clear. So it
obviously will will give China some kind
of understanding of the abilities
capabilities of the Indian military and
it will also it will also give China uh
some data about the performance or or
non-performance of their export versions
of the export versions of the weapon. So
it's it's good for China of course.
So China would have been watching this
with great interest and the data that
that they would have received will be
quite valuable to China. So the ideal
outcome for India was to end the
Pakistan threat once and for all. That
did not happen because uh the Americans
came in the way. Um so overall 100 days
analysis it was good. It boosted India's
morale. It gave gave us a it field
tested battle tested India's weapon
systems. And now it's very clear that
India has the world's best battle tested
air defense system in the world better
than the Israeli Iron Dome which
performed differently against the
Iranian ballistic and other missiles.
Right? So we have that we have very very
dangerous weapons in our our our
arsenal. So our made in India initiative
has been vindicated. Our weapons are
terrific
but uh that's where we are. Ideally we
would have wanted to end the Pakistan
threat once and for all but that not did
not happen. So at the end of the day
Pakistan in a few months we'll be able
to repair everything maybe buy more
weapons from whoever China, US wherever
and then we are back to square one. So
overall we did not honestly to be very
honest we did not gain anything. We did
not gain any territory. U the damage
done to Pakistan can be repaired.
Obviously the the the assets they lost
will be costly. Whether it is the Saab
2000 Awax aircraft, at least couple of
those. Whether it is the JF70s or the
five fighter planes that were shot down,
the runways that were damaged, the
hangars, the air the airports, air bases
that were damaged, those will be
repaired in a few months. Pakistan will
be back to where it was. They'll buy new
radars. They'll get some more fighter
planes. Maybe China will sell J20s or
whatever to ch to Pakistan, which will
make Pakistan give Pakistan an advantage
over India.
Uh overall nothing much came out of it.
Good. We taught Pakistan a lesson. A
bunch of Pakistani terrorists died. Now
the Pakistani terrorists know that they
can be hit anytime. So overall it it and
and it it uh one of the outcomes was
that India has now officially changed
its military doctrine. Any terror attack
emanating out of Pakistan will be
treated as an act of war. So that's
another positive. But overall we have
not we we treated some symptoms but we
have not treated the root cause of the
of the problem which is the existence of
Pakistan itself. So these are my
thoughts.
Okay. Bharata says is it fair to say
that it was always a USRussia fight with
Ukraine for well I've been saying that
for the past three years haven't I? It's
a proxy war. It's a US
uh initiated fight. Ukraine is the proxy
and the objective is to destroy Russia
hopefully. I mean that's that's the
maximum they can accomplish.
They haven't been a able to accomplish
this. And Barat says it's even more
obvious after Trump put in meet as
Zalinsky was nowhere in the picture.
Zalinski is a puppet.
Zalinski is unconstitutionally the
president of Ukraine right now. uh
according to the Ukraine constitution
there was supposed to be an election
last year sometime in May or whenever it
was May June whatever April May June you
can look up which which month it was
supposed to be the of course there is an
emergency that Zalinsky is imposed in
Ukraine and when there is an emergency
uh an election may not happen
but technically he should have there
should have been an election so he is
the emergency president of Ukraine
according to the constitution I'm not
sure if it's perfectly constitutionally
valid. And anyway, he is a puppet. He is
Ukraine underwent a regime change
operation in 2014. That's where all the
trouble started. So, Zalinsky is a
continuation of that artificial regime
that was put in in place in Ukraine by
the West. Uh so, yeah, it's it's a proxy
war. The objective is to destroy Russia
or at least degrade Russia's military
and economic capabilities. Hasn't worked
out. The the opposite has happened. So
Ukraine is the proxy. The Ukrainian
armed forces are the current foder and
the west is going to fight this war as
long as the last Ukrainian is willing to
fight or is is capable of fighting. So
clearly it's it's a fight between the US
and Russia instigated by the US not by
Russia. The Russians had to do this
otherwise all the red lines were being
crossed. So they had to do this.
Actually uh whatever the Russians did
they should have actually done it in
2014 not 2022. 2022 was a little late to
do that because it gave the West a lot
of time, ample time to arm Ukraine and
to bolster Ukraine's military
capabilities.
Anyhow,
okay, what next do we have? We have
Siddhant WMA says, "Turkey is hostile
towards Kuresh refugees, but they are
settling millions of sarcasian chants
inside their towns. Isn't it strange?"
Well, is it strange really? Is it? Well,
let me explain how I see this. Okay.
Turkey
map. Map. Let's look at the map. Yes.
Let me explain what the deal is with
Turkey. Okay. So, this is what Turkey
is. Turkey.
This large nation, reasonably large. uh
much of it is in Asia, Anatolia and a
little bit of it is in uh what used to
be called Thrace which is the European
part of Turkey. Now what's the history
of Turkey? The history of this
geographical region is that it used to
be Greek.
The whole of Anatolia was Greek.
There was zero Turkish people there a
thousand years ago. Let's say then the
Turks.
So, so when do the Turks start intruding
into this geographical region? It's in
the 1200s
mostly.
Before that, there were no Turks there.
The Turks, they lived in Central Asia.
They were a central Asian bunch of
tribes, the Turk tribes. Then something
happened in the 1200s that shook up the
whole of Central Asia. That was the rise
of Shri Chingghistan. So the Turks Turks
were fleeing from Changistan's
forces. So by while fleeing from
Changistan they entered Anatolia they
came down south between the Black Sea
and the Caspian Sea and that's how they
discovered Anatolia and that's how they
occupied conquered and occupied
Anatolia.
Eventually 1453 Constantinople falls
Byzantine Empire is dead and the Ottoman
Empire starts rises. There was a deal.
So this is captured territory. It has
never been Turk territory.
So that's why the Turks are super
hostile towards against the natives of
the territory, the real natives. So one
of the native
ethnicities, especially in eastern
Turkey, is the Kuresh people. Who are
the Kuresh people? They are an
Indo-Iranian people. They speak an
Iranic language. Do we know of any any
famous Kur history? Well, Salahadin
Saladin the magnificent or whatever he
is. Saladin, right? The the defender of
uh of uh he defended the Arab world, the
Islamic world against the crusaders,
right? So, he was a Kurd. So, the Kurds
their homeland is split between Iraq,
Iran and Turkey.
A significant number of Turkey is
actually Kurdistan. But the Turks have
taken it over and they have been
oppressing the Kurds uh for centuries.
So the Kurds are actually natives of
eastern Turkey but they are essentially
foreigners and second-ass citizens in
their own land. So that's why Turkey is
super hostile against the Kurds and the
Kurds have had a freedom movement which
the Turkish have designated as as a
terrorist movement. So that's why the
Turks have been super hostile against
the Kurds, but they are happy to bring
in other foreigners like Chachens and
Sarcasians
as long as it's not the native people of
the actual native people, the actual
indigenous people of the land. So kind
of explains things in short in brief
that's what I can tell you.
Um Rohan Allen says would a fully
marketed bricks currency trigger World
War II? It will trigger a massive
retaliation, massive response from the
US because it will be a genuine
challenge to the US dollar's supremacy
and hedgemony. Right? The BRICS nations
put together, they are a larger economic
block than the G7 nations. Now the G7
are all US vasals. US and its vasals. So
BRICS is is now a major economic block.
And if the BRICS nations can actually
somehow come together and actually
decide to to form a bricks currency,
that would be a major major challenge to
the supremacy of the US dollar and that
could completely shake up the American
economy
without the US dollar the US economy is
in shambles. It it it collapses.
So fully a bricks currency that that
that if it is actually formed created
and all the BRICS nations decide to to
exclusively use that well well that will
create that will trigger an economic
third world war for sure and maybe
something else. So yeah that will that
will be a it'll be a calamity for the US
and the US will take very very strong
and harsh measures um if this happens.
Hersh Nayan says, "Why doesn't India
mine its thorium reserves as as it can
be used as an alternative to the uranium
233 in nuclear energy program?" Well,
you see, India has a three-stage nuclear
program and
um
before we can start using thodium, we
need certain things to be there in
place,
a certain amount of uranium and so on.
Without that, you can't really um uh
operationalize the thorium reactors.
So that's why we are still stuck at the
end of the first stage and the second
and the beginning of the second stage. U
we have the world's largest thorium
reserves. No question about it. U what
about about a fourth of the entire
world's thorium reserves mostly on the
east coast of India the monazite sands
and so on. So we have that all we need
to do is to accelerate our nuclear
reactor program and the thorium research
program. Um, Prime Minister Modi said a
couple of days ago that we are now going
to, you know, go on mission mode and
build more reactors and have a certain
number of reactors by 2047.
Um, I think the earlier India does that,
the better it is because the moment we
can start operationalizing thodium, the
thorium reserves and start using those
in reactors, well, we will have an
essentially an unlimited uh amount of
energy, unlimited source of energy. So
we need to go through the second stage
of the of the u of the nuclear program
before we reach the third stage which is
thorium based reactors. So we are not
there yet unfortunately.
So right now mining the thorium mining
will be pretty easy I'm sure but right
now it will be of no use until we reach
the third stage of the nuclear program.
Premier League says makavelian why
doesn't Russia or China
why doesn't Russia or China give Iran
nuclear weapons if the US can keep
weapons of mass destructions in NATO
countries also Iran is a key ally for
Russia and China
while the US keeps nuclear weapons in
Pakistan
Pakistan I am
certain doesn't have an indigenous
nuclear weapons program
most likely those Those nuclear weapons,
those nuclear warheads are are American
warheads. That's I have no evidence to
back up this claim. But I am convinced
that these are American nuclear
warheads. And the American reaction to
certain events in operation Synindur
made it very very clear that the US has
very precious assets in Pakistan. Not
just those F-16s and and and the
technicians who babysit the F-16s, but
something else. Something else.
something far more valuable than a bunch
of 1980s F-16s.
Uh so now coming back to your question,
well Iran is a is a definitely a major
ally of both Russia and China
and China has this 25 year strategic
agreement with the uh in which China
will invest about I don't know $500
billion.
I don't know what what the actual number
was, but it's a massive investment in
Iran and Iran will in in in return sell
very cheap energy to to China. So, it's
a great deal that Chinese have with
Iran. Now, if Iran falls, let's say if
Iran if there's a regime change in in
Iran, that's a significant setback to
Russia as well as China. So, neither
nation Russia or China wants there to be
a regime change in Thran. They want the
current government, the current regime
to continue, right? And Israel wants a
regime change in Iran. The US wants a
regime change in Thran. Both both both
of them they want it. So what is the one
thing that can prevent regime change?
What what's the one thing that can
guarantee that a regime change operation
won't happen? It's nuclear weapons. Look
at North Korea, how secure they are,
right? Very poor nation, but they are
super secure because they have nuclear
weapons. the US won't dare bother them,
won't dare cross any red lines with with
North Korea.
So the question then is so why doesn't
Russia or China give Iran nuclear
weapons?
Well, one thing, Iran has its own
nuclear program. It may not be a nuclear
weapons program, but they are they have
been trying to enrich uranium for the
past, I don't know how many years, at
least 15 years. Yeah.
Um, and they probably may have enough
enriched uranium today for a handful of
nuclear warheads. They probably may have
it. Uh, but are they afraid to to
declare themselves a nuclear power? Are
they afraid to do a couple of tests? I'm
not sure what it is. I am pretty sure
that by now they would have at least
enough uh 90% plus enriched uranium for
a few nuclear weapons. That's number
one.
Secondly,
Israel is a nuclear power
and it would not tolerate Iran becoming
a nuclear weapons power. And if Russia,
let's say Russia gives let's say 20
nuclear weapons to to Iran. I think that
will be seen as a major provocation by
by Israel as well as the US and it may
create complications for Russia
possibly. The same goes for China. China
is trying its best to not attract more
US tariffs. It still wants to
participate in the in the world economic
order in a variety of ways especially
when it comes to trading with the EU
nations and other things like that. And
if China let's say supplies nuclear
weapons to Iran then it would make China
a pariah and all China's trade with the
EU also will end and and it will face
major consequences. So I think there are
there are multiple hidden factors like
these hidden second and third order and
fourth order effects that these nations
don't want to bear.
Uh so that's most likely why these
nations are not supplying Iran with
nuclear weapons. Mr. Putin actually had
offered to take all of Iran's missile
material and store it in Russia in in
case the west has a problem with Iran
having uh enriched highly enriched
uranium. So actually Mr. Putin was
offering to do the reverse not to give
nuclear weapons but to take away the
file material. So clearly there are
these calculations at play over here.
Okay.
Sai says how do gas routes shape Europe?
I'm sorry, what? How do gas routes shape
Europe?
I'm not sure what the question means.
U see Europe, it needs energy, right?
And u
it used to import Russian gas.
So those gas pipelines were either
overland, some of them were overland and
some of them were undersea like the Nord
Stream 2 pipeline which was destroyed by
the US. Well, allegedly, allegedly.
So, these are the gas routes that Europe
had and they were supplying energy to
Europe. Beyond that, I don't know how
gas routes can shape a continent. I
mean, an alleged continent. Europe is
not really a continent. It's part of
Eurasia, a minor part of Eurasia, but
whatever. Gas routes don't shape a
continent. The geography of a of a
continent shapes the continent.
Unless it's something else you are
meaning. godliness says space war, AI,
quantum computing and biotech will shape
the new realities of geopolitics and
human thought for the foreseeable
future.
Hence, which three countries you feel
will lead the way forward and why? Okay,
like I've said so many times in the past
3 4 years, um the two or three nations
that will lead the world in space
exploration in the 21st century will be
the two or three nations that will
decide and shape the destiny of the rest
of humanity.
So space a nation's space capabilities
are a great indicator of its overall
technological progress. Of course,
artificial intelligence, quantum
computing, biotech, these are all
emerging technologies which are also
like at the cutting edge of the
technological realm and all of these
technologies have side effects have have
a military dimension which is why they
are so important geopolitically. How? If
you are a great space power, well, you
can deploy weapons in space. Weapons
that can't be intercepted. That's one
very easy example. Artificial
intelligence. Well, if you if you are at
the forefront of AI, then it it it gives
you the kind of intelligence your
adversary can't have, right? Instead of
searching for talent, you just use AI to
do all the all the analysis and make
predictions, make forecasts and and uh
determine what's the best strategy for
so and so military campaign in a way
that no human being human being can. And
if you can equip your weapons with AI,
well, it makes them also smart. So if
your adversary doesn't have the AI
capabilities that you have then you have
a clear advantage and you will win
quantum computing once again encryption
and so much more biotechnology well well
you can decimate entire populations
without firing a single bullet if you
have bio technology. So all of these
technologies are are obviously going to
shape the new realities like you say
goodliness of geopolitics and so on.
Which three countries will will lead the
way forward? The US and China are
obvious answers. Now who else is there?
Europe. You Europe is a bunch of vasal
nations. They don't really matter. Will
it be Japan? Japan is a vasal,
unfortunately. Is it South Korea? South
Korea is a vasal unfortunately.
Australia. Australia is owned by the US.
Who do we have? The two alternatives are
India and and Russia. So, it's the US
and China and maybe India or Russia or
maybe both. We'll see. It all depends on
so many factors. What does India How
does India approach this? Does India
take this seriously? I think the
government of India is taking the these
technologies very seriously. But will
they be able to get get the results?
That's the question. For that you need
reforms in so many so many sectors.
Shall I say it education
and you need you know um reforms in in
the sense that you know uh you need to
cut down the red tape you need to cut
down all the procedural nonsense the BS
uh end corruption so many things you
have to do. So will India be able to get
it done? In Russia, I think it's lagging
when it comes to AI. I don't see any AI
coming out of Russia. They are obviously
technologically very advanced in some
technologies like probably bio
biotechnology. So I think it's the US,
China and
one or both of Russia and and and India.
Ajit J says Mr. Modi finally spoke about
demographic change in the east. Well,
I'm so glad. I'm so glad he did.
Finally. He he so now it's what he
announced on the 15th of August from the
red fort is that India is going to
undertake a major demographic mission or
initiative
and he said that the the Guspetier the
infiltrators are a major threat to the
country. Well it's so so good to hear
this. Now we need to get rid of the
infiltrators. we may have uh who knows
maybe a 100 million infiltrators who are
squatting in our territory and he spoke
about the east so mainly it's Bangladesh
but it's also the infiltration that's
coming in from Myanmar right the cookie
terrorists who are squatting in Manipur
they also need to be thrown out right so
yeah we have two major challenges one is
the illegal immigration that's coming in
infiltration that's coming from
Bangladesh the second is the illegal
infiltration that's a consequence of
project K cookie land for Christ These
two problems need to be addressed and
Mr. Modi did not name any nation but
it's pretty clear he was he was talking
about both. So I'm hopeful that the
government of India will take this very
seriously as soon as possible and start
taking action
right away hopefully. So very pleased to
hear what Mr. Modi had to say. I'm very
pleased to hear that.
Okay. Okay. Naman Singh says based on
the rumors, do you think it's possible
for the US deep state to change regime
in India like Bangladesh and Pakistan
also? You will avoid this but every day
there's a drama in India. How will we
grow?
You will avoid this but every day
there's a drama in India. How will we
grow? It disturbs everyone. Are you
talking about are you talking about
political dramas or something else? I'm
not sure. But yeah, I'm not I'm not
sure. The look overall there's drama in
India. There's drama in India all the
time. Indians keep arguing with with
each other. Indians keep fighting each
other. There's always some some
political issue somewhere. Sometimes it
is pigeon, sometimes it is dogs,
sometimes it is something,
right? Always focus on the insignificant
things and and so that you know people.
So there's all kinds of political issues
in India. I I will not comment on those.
How will we grow? We can only grow if we
if we are united and the entire system
is designed to divide us to keep us
divided. That's the problem that we are
saddled with. the system that we have
inherited from 1947. It's the worst
possible system but it's the system that
has given us the leadership that we have
today. So that's the con conundrum. Now
based on the rumors I don't know about
the rumors but uh do you think it's
possible for the US deep state to change
regime in India like Bangladesh and
Pakistan? Well they will try they will
try they they are trying various
experiments. They're already allying
with certain they are already allegedly
allying with some political parties in
India. They are already clearly engaging
in what they call subnational diplomacy
which means that you you you try to
create divisions in India by aligning
with various local regional political
parties and giving them special
treatment and stops and benefits and
whatnot privileges and then using that
to create situations that are beneficial
for US objectives in India. uh they are
we know that uh we know how much well
you may not know it but a tremendous
amount of money has been flowing into
India for Christian conversion
activities industrial scale demographic
conversion activities in India coming
from the US you know possibly billions
maybe even trillions of dollars over
over many years to change the religion
in India convert people to Christianity
right it's it's a it's an industrial
scale program
u so that obviously see the thing about
Christianity like the Japanese have
written about it and the Chinese have
written about it is that when people
convert to this foreign religions they
somehow spontaneously develop extra
territorial loyalties not
extraterrestrial ambitions
extr territorial loyalties which means
they start becoming loyal to foreign
powers not your own country and so
that's why conversion to this foreign
religion is a very well it it it it
helps you destroy a nation
Um
so they have the the American deep state
let's say is putting all the pieces in
in place in India to eventually someday
effect a regime change operation. No
question about it. The best thing for
them is is that you know Mr. Modi is not
in power and somebody who is about
onetenth as capable as Mr. Modi should
be in power. somebody who's an absolute
idiot hypothetically hypothetical person
right I mean if you want to vasalize the
nation you want an idiot to rule the
nation someone in Indian version let's
say of Zalinski
who will sell his country to foreign
powers that's what they want
um so right now it is difficult see in
2024 elections they they tried they
tried to influence the course of the
elections using propag propaganda media
and all that and it is alleged it is
alleged that various India Indian media
houses are also allegedly
aligned
with the deep with with the US
so 24 they tried maybe they will try in
29 maybe they'll try before that so yeah
it's it's a great outcome for the US if
they can uh effect a regime change in
India just like what they did in in
Pakistan east and west Pakistan I mean
ideal outcome for them then India will
be embraced wholeheartedly and
completely vasalized and it'll be
another East India Company kind of
situation. So there you have it.
Godliness says the swift the swift
expansion of the Chinese Navy is scary.
Their one destroyer carries more than
100 missiles.
Uh 132 missile. No, one second. How
much?
128 missiles. Yeah. Um so one Chinese
destroyer carries more than 100 missiles
equal to four Indian destroyers. The
real threat will always be China and we
need west at least for now. For what?
What will the West do? If there's a war
between India and China, do you think
the West will intervene? They'll be
happy to see both countries bash each
other's brains out.
What will the West do? You think the
West is friendly to India?
The West wants India to fail. The West
wants India to be balconized. The West
wants India's economy to crumble and
crash and burn. And they want the same
for China. If there is a conflict
between India and China, the West will
eat popcorn and and throw fuel in the
fire. What are you talking about, sir?
It's not Be a little more realistic,
sir. That's what I would say. Uh I agree
that the swift expansion of the Chinese
Navy is scary. I completely agree.
That's something we have been witnessing
since the 1990s. So, what have we done
about it? It's not something that
happened now, right? They have been
slowly, steadily, gradually, slowly
building their capacities, their
capabilities. It's been a very long,
arduous, slow process.
They did not build up this naval might
overnight.
In the 1990s, the Americans used to
laugh about the Chinese Navy. Today,
they don't now laugh at all. They're
scared.
Right. And yes, you are right. One
Chinese destroyer typically has VLS
tubes. What? 128 I think. 128 VLS tubes.
The big ones. The big destroyers. 128 VS
tubes. How many missiles do Indian
destroyers carry? 16.
16. Is it or is it is it 32? I think the
most is 32. I don't think there's any 64
VLS destroyer in India. So, what are we
doing about it? That's my question. The
Chinese Navy has been expanding since
the 1990s. What have we been doing about
it?
How many more destroyers did we acquire
in the past 10 years? How many
submarines did we acquire in the past 10
years? If we do do nothing about it, we
can't blame the Chinese for it.
The real strength, the only measure of
the strength of a navy is the number of
missiles they can deploy at sea on a on
any given day. Not the number of
destroyers you have. Oh, we may we have
these many destroyers. How many missiles
can we deploy? So, these are hard facts
for the Indian government and the Indian
Navy. They need to do something about
this. The Chinese Navy may be stuck in
the east because of the Taiwan issue,
the South China Sea issue and the threat
that they pursue from Japan and South
Korea and the US. But if they decide the
Chinese to deploy 1/4 of of their navy
to the Bay of Bengal, we'll be in so
much trouble. We you you cannot imagine
it. So India needs to do something about
this. And and if there is an issue, the
West will not come to India's rescue.
Please disabuse yourself of this of this
notion. The west will eat popcorn and
enjoy
enjoy and they will throw fuel on the
fire.
Okay. Deepakata says Bill Gates big
farmer global war on public health like
COVID inflated fear like swine flu in
the past and road shield global control
financial. What's your question sir?
What is your question? Look we know the
US pharma industry is a parasitical
industry. They don't want to cure
anyone. They want lifelong patients.
They want lifelong customers. The entire
model is is such that you they want to
hook everybody on pills. You go to the
US and see what these people have in
their you know in their bathroom the mir
the cabinet behind the mirror. Bunch of
bottle after bottle of pills. Every
American takes like 10 20 pills every
day. Even healthy healthy looking people
they take pills for what God only knows.
You have this symptom take that pill. It
created side effects take that pill.
more side effects, take this one.
They have hooked everybody on on these
drugs
and uh the US food industry and
pharmaceutical industry complement each
other. So there is this war on tobacco
which is so evil, right? Tobacco is very
we know that tobacco isn't good. So they
have banned tobacco. I mean tobacco is
is is now considered to be a well not a
very very uh respectable thing to do,
right? But if you eat their food, it's
probably worse than than consuming
tobacco. The food itself over there is
so bad. So the entire US economy is
based on exploiting people, their own
people. The highest obesity rates in the
world in the 1970s, nobody was obese
obese. What happened? What happened
after 1971?
So they want to control the rest of the
world in this manner. And that's why the
Indian government is unwilling to accept
US agricultural exports which is one of
the major bones of contention because
that will that way they will enslave
India and we don't want that.
Shubhham Kumbakar says Kumbhakar says
let's assume the world war ended without
nukes. Excuse me what let's okay let's
let's read let's read let's assume the
world war II happens and it ends without
a nuclear exchange. Can that lead to a
one world government? All the wars in
human history, human greed for power,
all of this is leading to one world
government. Do you think it's happening?
Look, interesting question by the way.
See, human greed is endless.
Human greed is endless. When when a
person tastes power, you know, we don't
know the full extent of our own human
nature. We think we're all good people.
But the moment you taste a bit of power,
what is power? people obeying you
without question. Unquestioning
obedience. Get this done. It'll be done.
Wow. That's intoxicating.
And you want to expand that. You want
more and more people to obey you
unquestioningly.
Right?
Let's say you are an emperor. You are
the head of an empire. You control let's
say onethird of the world. Imagine how
intoxicating that is. But then once you
are are hooked to that, once you're
addicted to that, you want more and more
and more. it will never end. So
eventually the objective of the great
powers is to control the entire world
and all the resources and uh have all
the people obeying them. That's what it
is. So yeah, the objective of the west
is a one world government. They want to
control the entire world. They want the
entire world to come come under the
control. That's essentially what one
world government is.
One world, one government. Um
now the question is let's assume world
war 3I ends without nukes. Okay, let's
say there is a world war 3
in which all the major powers are all
involved and at the end of the day when
it's over one power comes out of that
standing everybody else is gone and
nukes were not used which means the
world still exists it's not been
destroyed will it lead to a world one
world one government most likely most
likely do I see it happening very
unlikely world war II will mean a
nuclear exchange nobody will yeah that's
the unfortunate thing about World War II
it will inevitably lead to a nuclear
exchange, a massive nuclear exchange. So
there will be no world, no government.
That's what will be the outcome.
Dave says, "Sar your views on high
powered demography task force." Exactly.
That was what I was talking about the
high powered demography task force
announced by Mr. Modi on the 15th of
August and he urged Indians to make our
own jet engine social media etc. Well,
this is something I have been speaking
about for the for the past four years
since since the day the Ask show
started, right? I have been speaking
about that.
I've been saying this is what we need in
the country. So, Mr. Modi has said this
on the 5th of August from the ramparts
of the Red Fort. I'm so happy to hear
that. Uh so, a high-powered demography
task force to to to get rid of all the
foreign infiltrators squatting in our
land. Well, thank you so much, Modi G.
Please get it done. Even if it takes a
decade to get it done because removing a
100 million possibly infiltrators is not
something you can do in a few weeks,
maybe a decade, maybe two decades, I
don't care. As long as the process
starts and it's it's done properly,
let's say in two decades all the
infiltrators are gone. It'll be a huge
relief for the country. So it's very
good to hear the announcement of this
initiative. Now we would like to see how
it's executed. I hope it's executed well
and I hope that other institutions don't
come and stand in the way.
uh he urged Indians to make our own jet
engine social media. Well, once again
very good uh
very good thing to say and look Indians
when it comes to jet engines the
government has to be involved in that
because it's a tremendous amount of
money that needs to be invested in
making a jet engine. So what Indians can
do let's say you're an entrepreneur you
want to make a jet engine you'll be able
to make a 20 kon new jet engine which
could be used for a drone perhaps but to
have a 100 kon newton jet engine you
will have to invest hundreds of millions
maybe hundreds of tens of billions of
dollars that is something only the
government can do so maybe it indicates
that Mr. Modi is very very uh he is
determined that India will produce an
indigenous jet engine. Well that that's
that's brilliant. What else can we can
we ask for social media? Well, I think
entrepreneurs can come up with that you
know. So overall it was a very very good
speech very positive speech. So many
good things to hear and one would like
to see the execution of that. So overall
it was great.
Okay.
Backbenture Academy lover says, "Is
Italy better for tourism or Norway?" How
is this a geopolitical question?
I think it depends on you. Whatever you
like. Okay, but let's let's stick to
geopolitics please. Adipuru says in
Punjab 10th May noon so movement of
tanks and armored vehicles via
via N national highway to borders
towards boris towards borders. Was there
a plan of government of ground invasion
and Uncle Sam stopped us stopped us?
It's possible because the the logical
end point of a war
is the achievement of your political
objectives and national security
objectives. That's the end point. That's
the logical end point of a war. You
don't start a war just to stop it
without achieving the objectives. So if
Uncle Sam had not stopped us, maybe we
would have taken back P. It's possible.
or maybe even bifurcated Pakistan. So
yeah, Uncle Sam stopped us, Trump
stopped us, otherwise today would be a
different situation. So it tells you who
India's real adversaries are. I hope
that people make a note of that.
MK says, "Is the US the dangerous empire
given that it's okay with its own
population taking GMOs, pharmaceuticals,
narcotic drugs, demographic engineers to
wipe its own religion in Europe through
illegal im immigration?"
Well, I just kind of spoke about this,
but okay. Um, yeah, it's okay with its
own population taking GMOs. It's ruining
the health of its population. Its
population is a set of bunch of 300
million guinea pigs essentially who are
captive who are captive to the food
industry and the pharmaceutical industry
both of which are poisoning the people
of the US.
Every American knows this by now that
it's the food that's poisoning them.
It's the pharmaceuticals that's
poisoning them. And narcotics narcotics
in the US everybody takes drugs at some
point in their life. I'm not talking
about drugs as in medicines. I'm talking
about narcotics, cocaine,
heroinum, cocaine, heroin, what crystal
meth like Breaking Bad and whatnot.
Everybody does drugs at some point in
their life. How are drugs so readily
available? The US says that it's got the
best uh homeland security and best uh um
police system in the world police force.
Why are drugs so readily available at
every street corner that 15-year-old
kids can get drug can can overdose on
drugs?
It's the world's most corrupt country,
right?
Uh demographic engineering to wipe
Christianity out of Europe. Well, yeah,
that's also happening. Yes. So, yeah,
when when you are all powerful, you can
do anything. And then it then
one has to see whether the power is used
for good or evil and the power is not
being used for very very good purposes
right now unfortunately and that pattern
has continued for a very long time. So
you are right sir. You are right. All
empires are dangerous.
No question. All empires are dangerous.
If you if you fall a foul of an empire,
you may have to pay very big price.
Aran Singh says, "What's your view on
the MK1A? Are they great great jets that
the IF can use? Is it really capable
against the quality quantity of China?"
Thank you. Okay. I don't know.
I am not a defense expert. So I have I I
don't know how the the mark So right now
you're mark 1 A right
but here's what I here's how I see the
the program. It is one step in a long
process. Now we know how to manufacture
our own fighter jets. The only missing
component is a jet engine. So if you
know how to manufacture a I think it's a
good I don't know if it's a great
fighter plane. I think it's a good
fighter plane from everything I've seen.
I'm not an illiterate when it comes to
defense.
uh since I was like 3 years old I've
been as a kid I was obsessed with
aircraft I used to make my own you know
model aircrafts and all that so and u I
have studied the history of war so I
have some understanding of aircraft but
I am I don't classify myself as a
defense expert but I think that the is a
good fighter plane I'm not sure if it's
great maybe it is maybe it is but it's
definitely a good fighter plane
now we going
produce more versions, different
versions of the theas and the learnings
we have incorporated from our experience
in developing the theasis fighter plane
after all the trials and tests and
trials all those learnings are going to
be incorporated into future fighter
planes like the AMCA like the potential
TB TE twin engine deckbased fighter and
other fighter planes in the future. So
it's a great learning experience. It's a
it's a good fighter plane and that
guarantees that the next iterations of
the fighter planes we produce will be
like excellent increasingly better
quality. So that's how I see the the I
think it's a good fighter plane. I think
it'll be it's it's definitely most
likely better than the Mig 21. The Mig21
took down an F-16.
So that's a good comparison there.
Right. So I think pages program is super
valuable for India in so many different
ways.
AVM says uh it appears as if opposition
in India is acting on on queue on
foreign agenda coherent with regime
change operations. How what can
government do to contain this? Look I
don't comment about domestic political
matters but you have also a component of
regime change operations that come from
abroad. So I will not comment about any
political party or internal politics.
What can the government of India do to
contain for an agenda that u
about which is coherent with regime
change operations?
Yeah. So how does the government of
India deal with that? Let's say you have
the the embassy and consulates of a very
powerful very major nations nation that
are trying to further a regime change
agend regime change operation agenda in
India by let's say aligning
hypothetically with allegedly
hypothetically with various Indian
regional parties or or other opposition
parties potentially hypothetically
completely completely allegedly what do
you do about that well it depends right
if that power is so powerful then what
do you do with that? So I think this is
a matter of dealing with with this issue
at an internal political level
and that involves dealing with local
politicians. Maybe you have a local
politician Mr. X or Mrs. X or whatever
Miss X who is on the payroll allegedly
hypothetically of a foreign power. How
do you deal with them? Well, that's all
internal politics. I'm sure there are
ways and means of doing that. I mean
let's say you take a 100 Indian Indian
politicians I think it is pretty likely
that more than 50 of them could
potentially be corrupt people right
potentially potentially hypothetically
so if somebody is corrupt I think you
have a tremendous amount of leverage on
them if they have intelligent corruption
so my point is this is all politics it's
all dirty politics and it can be dealt
Anonymous scientist says, "I joined a
little late. What leverage does Russia
have over the US?" A larger nuclear
arsenal, the largest territory in the
world.
Um,
that's two very obvious examples.
Um, it has the upper hand in the Ukraine
conflict. That is leverage.
It has been able to withstand all all
the US sanctions and still grow its
economy.
Russia's economy is growing. Russia's
economy is doing well. Its GDP is
growing
faster than the other euro European
economies. The millions of sanctions the
US has imposed on Russia have failed to
destroy the Russian economy. It's been
super resilient. Russia's industrial
base is doing well. All of these things
are all of these factors are leverage
against the US. When do you use leverage
in negotiations?
Right. So when Trump and Putin meet,
Putin will say, "Look, look, Donald,
I I currently occupy 1/4 of Ukraine
territory. Tomorrow I take more. So why
should you fight? Do you want me to go
and take more? Let's just end the
fighting and give me half of Ukraine."
That's leverage. What leverage does
Trump have? He's already imposed all the
sanctions.
What more will it do? What leverage does
he have? So this these are examples of
leverage that nations have and Russia
has plenty of leverage over the US right
now. Russia is in a position of
strength. Now uh what leverage does the
US have? Well, they own NATO, they own
the EU, so that gives them leverage and
so on.
Rywick says how was she Hassina actually
removed? Was it was it because of
students or some other power? How was
Hina beneficial for India? Can she or
her kids come to power? Look, Shik
Kasina was was was
good for India because she ended
Bangladesh's role as East Pakistan. For
the longest time when when her
predecessor Khaled Zia was in power,
Bangladesh was used by the ISI to train
uh terrorists who would then be
infiltrated into India's far east into
Assam into various other parts of India
and they will wreak havoc. You had
various separatist movements in India's
far east that were all nurtured in
Bangladesh. Those militants were given
training. They were given supplies. All
of that in Bangladesh. So many of these
things activities were happening and
overall Shik Hasina Khaled Khaled Zia's
regime was extremely virulently
aligned against against India with
Pakistan with everybody else with
whoever was anti-India.
Now Shik Kasina comes to power and she
changes the track entirely and she ended
all these she destroyed she she had all
these terrorist and and separatist
training camps dismantled and all those
people handed over brought to justice
either incarcerated in Bangladesh or
whoever was India was India wanted was
given to India all of that ended and
whatever issues we had with Bangladesh
all of those were mostly resolved all
those enclaves and exclaves that we had
those were that issue was resolved. So
many of these issues were resolved
because of Shikhasina's willingness to
um to have a positive attitude and and a
good approach towards India and
obviously that's not good if you are
anti-India if you want to contain India
that's why Shakasina was removed how was
she removed it was not the godamn
students who removed Shakasina where
today if the students brought brought
about a revolution then they would be
ruling the country today it's some
89year-old gizer who's running the
country Muhammad
Right.
And he himself is not ruling the
country. He's just the puppet face.
Who's ruling the country? It's the army.
Why did Sri Kasina leave Bangladesh?
Because the army gave her half an hour
to leave. You leave in half an hour.
Otherwise, we can't guarantee your
security, which is a death threat.
That's why she left. Where does the real
power lie? Political power flows out of
the barrel of a gun. It was the army
that removed Shika Sina. Now
noman Singh says uh is to be TBC
to be clear is is regime change possible
it's possible everything is possible
that's why India has to be super careful
sait says why is Voke culture mostly
American not European well the origins
are in Europe
the origins are in Europe
uh let you can trace back the origins
back in time as as far back you want, as
far back as you want. You could trace it
to the to the 1790s. Possibly
you could trace it to
300 AD roughly.
You could trace it back to various eras.
But let's let's talk about the 20th
century.
Okay? So there was this uh
post-modernist movement in Europe.
uh Jacqu Deida Fuko and various such
so-called philosophers who wrote a lot
of garbage that you can't understand but
it sounds very intellectual
and uh their their position was that you
know
was that
it was a neo-xist position essentially
basically to to keep it very simple it
was a neo-xist position and they brought
in Marxism by the via the back door and
all of that was then propagated to the
US where um the US education system took
that up. Postmodernism,
various various disguised forms of
Marxism and all of that eventually
transmorphed or transmogrified into what
we now call Voke culture. So its origins
are European but it's now mostly
American and now America is exporting it
to other parts of the world including
back into Europe.
Ra Ragul says, "Why does Israel and the
US fear Iran so much? Is Iran that
powerful? How is Iran so advanced in
missile technology and able to develop
strong defense systems despite it's a
deprived condition?
Look, Persia has always been a major
power.
Very ancient civilization,
right? I don't know how many maybe 5,000
years old, at least 3,000 years old. And
they have always been very powerful. And
historically Persia always fought the
west, never India. Never went eastwards.
Always fought the west. And that's
history. That's old history. Um today
Iran, well they are resourcerich,
tremendous tremendous oil and gas
supplies. Yes. And uh good population,
large population. And if a nation
acquire if a nation like that with that
large land mass with with tremendous oil
and gas supplies acquires nuclear
weapons, it transforms into a beast.
It can transform into a beast. It can
wipe Pakistan off the of the map of the
world if it wants to. It can also wipe
Iran the map of the world. Israel off
the map of the world. And that's why
um Israel doesn't like Iran, fears Iran.
And also because the Iranian regime
since 1979 has been very strongly
anti-Israel and anti- West
and they have well they have said that
Israel has no right to exist. That's
what the Iranian government's position
has been since 1979. So obviously Israel
will take it seriously and now if a
nation that says you don't have the
right to exist starts the process of
developing nuclear weapons, you will
take it hyper seriously and that's the
situation. Okay. And obviously um Iran
and the US since 79 have had a very
fraught relationship. How did the 79
Islamic revolution happen? By out by
overthrowing a US puppet Muhammad Rai.
So the US had a great situation in
Persia in Iran and the 1979 revolution
destroyed that.
So the US lost control of Iran and
that's why they would like to regain
control of Iran and that's why uh they
want to do a regime change operation if
possible there. Hopefully that explains
the situation.
James says, "Old European architecture
much better than Indian." Well, you see
James, back when you were constructing
those men called the Stonehenge,
we had a fully
fully metropolitan urbanized
civilization with architecture that you
cannot contemplate.
Anyhow, you may I I grant you permission
to keep on believing what you wish to
continue. James Curio
literally officer K says, "Why do so
many American politicians donate to
EIPC?
Shouldn't it be classified as a foreign
entity? I would never imagine doing this
to another for another nation." Okay,
listen. I am completely ignorant about
these matters. Okay, let me let me
proclaim my complete innocence on these
matters. Let's let's find out what is
AIPAC.
What is it? Uh let's go to Google
American product, right? AIPAC.
What?
What is that?
Yes. AIPAC.
American Israel Public Affairs
Committee. Oh, I didn't know. It's a
pro-Israel lobbying group in the United
States. Oh.
AIPAC works to influence US foreign
policy particularly regarding the
relationship between the US and Israel.
They advocate for policies that support
Israel and work to strengthen the
USIsrael alliance.
Detail look AIPAC lobbying. It's a major
player in the Israel lobby in the US.
The Israel lobby where have I heard
this? John Mirshimer somewhere. Okay.
And it includes various groups and
individuals who advocate for policies
favorable to Israel. Well, well, well.
It's considered to be one of the most
influential lobbying groups in the US
with a significant impact on US and
Israel relations and Bob and broader US
foreign policy. It's not a political
action committee, but it does engage in
political activity, including
fundraising for Okay. It's faced
criticism for its influence in the role
in shaping US policy towards Israel. It
p some people argue that it prioritizes
Israeli interests over US foreign policy
goals. It stated stated focus is
strengthening the US Israel relationship
but it's also been criticized for
supporting policies that consider some
consider harmful to Palestinian press
and so on. Oh wow. Okay. So that is the
AIPC American Israel public affairs
committee
and it looks like from what literally
officer K is saying it looks like many
American politicians so many of them
donate to the AIPAC.
That's interesting. Why do they do that?
Maybe the US. So the US is a Christian
nation. Look, how do I see this? The US
is a Christian nation despite officially
they may not have a religion but they
are a Christian nation and Christianity
has emerged from Judaism. So maybe maybe
these US politicians who may have these
very conservative vote banks etc. They
and they may believe in Lord Jesus
Christ and all maybe they they may feel
that you know because it all came from
Judaism we should support the Holy Land
and support an organization that works
for better relations between the US and
the Holy Land. Maybe that's the reason
why US politicians donate to the AIPC. I
can't think of any other reason.
Yeah. Should it be classified as a
foreign entity? Well, if it's
incorporated in the US or whatever, if
it's uh based in the US, maybe it's not
a foreign entity. Even if it lobbies for
um the cause of better relations with a
foreign country. Yeah. Uh would India do
this for another nation? No. No. But
India is an is a civilization. The US is
an artificial nation by the way. True
true fact. India is a civilization
thousands of years old. We won't do that
for anybody else. We have some
selfrespect. The US is an artificial
nation.
artificially constructed nation
constructed by a bunch of settler colon
colonizers
right who came from elsewhere so they
they may have allegiances to other
nations that that's you see that's the
difference between the US and India very
different kinds of nations we India are
a civilization state the US is a settler
colonial state very different situation
and that's why maybe it's possible over
there for for this sort of situation to
arise
that's what I can say sir Okay. Okay.
Sarat Biswar says why what is our
government or organizations in our
country doing to absorb the Indian
talent that measures what measures need
to be taken compared to the west or
China?
First of all, make it super easy to do
business in India. Cut down all the red
tape. Secondly, end all the corruption.
Launch a war on corruption, alleged
corruption. Third, recognize merit in
India.
This reservations nonsense has to end at
some point in time. Fourthly, reform the
education system. Make it completely
merit-based and make it an education
system that nurtures, seeks out,
identifies and nurtures talent instead
of doing the opposite.
You do all of this, India will be
transformed, unleashed, unshackled,
right? Uh but it's easier said than
done. The whole system allegedly
allegedly runs on corruption and red
tape and all that. So how do you do
that? Yeah.
Solo Leveling says, "Can India remove
all illegal immigrants completely?"
Well, it's impossible to ever remove all
illegal immigrants. But how about we
remove 95% of them at least? That can be
done once we are done with 95%. Then
instead of let's say hypothetically 100
million, we'll only have 5 million. Then
start the next phase of of of deporting
95% of those. You take it step by step.
It's impossible to ever remove
everything or all all the cancer but
remove remove as much as you can. So I I
am pretty confident it can happen over
the next 20 years.
Djamat says a new narrative about Modi
BJP having rigged elections is being
perpetuated. Is there a regime change
being attempted by the US? What are the
chances of it succeeding like in
Pakistan or Bangladesh? Look, I don't I
have not heard of this narrative. Maybe
there are whispers and or maybe shouts
of that somewhere within internal Indian
politics. I don't comment about that.
Could it have
a US hand very much? Potentially
hypothetically it's possible
it's possible. So you know the objective
if such a thing is true if if let's say
a foreign country wants to create this
this new narrative that Mr. Modi uh or
the BJP allegedly according to these
foreigners rigged elections if if so by
just repeating a lie over and over again
and having that lie amplified by
opposition allegedly politicians
hypothetically
and just keep on doing it over and over
again. You can convince a lot of idiots
in the country
that it's true. Not just idiots, a lot
of innocent people who don't understand
the these these devious tactics. It's
possible to to convince a lot of
innocent people that this is true by
having this repeated in a chorus over
and over again by various politicians
hypothetically and having this amplified
by various Indian media houses and
foreign media houses. It it can be done.
So that would not lead to immediate
regime change but regime change could
then be easier in maybe five or 10 years
maybe 5 years maybe even 2 three years
what are the what are the chances of
something like this succeeding like in
Pakistan or Bangladesh the chances in
India are lower than in Pakistan or
Bangladesh in Pakistan Bangladesh it's
so easy just ask the army to do whatever
you want and it'll be done it happens
overnight in India you have to use the
pro the the the system to do it so it's
it's more difficult In India, it takes
longer time. It takes patience on the
part of the foreign entity. But it's
possible. It is possible. So that's why
you see India is in a tight spot right
now. All these all these methods will be
used against us.
The objective is to destroy India's
potential.
The objective
is to bring to power some hypothetical
politician that I'm not aware of but
somebody who will be incapable of of
running the country properly and they
will run the economy into the ground
like what Mr. Borisen did to Russia and
what Mr. Zalinski is doing to Ukraine
that sort of thing. Okay.
Saiti already says do US tech giants
threaten India's sovereignty? Not
directly but yeah technological
sovereignty for sure. So if the
government of India decides that why do
we need our own search engine? Why do we
need our own AI? Let's just buy it from
the US. Let's just uh use that. Well
that that very seriously threatens
India's technological sovereignty. So
indirectly yes it does threaten India's
sovereignty.
Paid says I recently heard from Mr. Pank
Zaran exuty NSA uh on a podcast where
that Russia has used Pakistan against us
in the past. Is it true? Well, of
course. I spoke about this about an hour
ago in on in this live stream.
I'll just give you some examples. I'll
not talk about Russia using Pakistan
against us, but I'll give you some
examples. In around 2015, Russia sold a
bunch of military helicopters to
Pakistan.
And around 2015 onwards for m for for a
number of years more than five six years
seven years possibly Russia and Pakistan
started having these annual military
exercises together where Russian troops
and Pakistani troops would do military
exercises together. These were called
the durjba exercises. Durba means
friendship in Russian. So that was there
um
and so on. Yeah, there could there could
be more of these things. So that that's
been there. Russia and Pakistan have
tangled together, flirted together in
the past. You have to always be
cognizant of the these facts. You see my
point is this my friends. This question
I let me utilize it to make a bigger
point. There are some Indians who
imagine that some countries are our best
friends. I'll not name the countries.
There are some Indians who imagine that
certain countries are our best friends
and they put that those countries flags
on their on their social media profiles.
Let me tell you something. Nobody is our
friend. Okay? You will have nations
aligning with us when they're in where
when it satisfies their interests.
But the moment we are of no use, nobody
will align with us. The only people who
will stand with us are our own people.
Us Indians. Remember that. So stop
worshiing certain countries.
And I'm speaking about at least one
country apart from Russia over here.
Stop worshiping certain countries. have
some dignity and self-respect? Okay,
Indians, enough of this. I'm I'm just
sick of this.
Arun Kumar says, "Is a regime change
possible in Iran? Major foreign polls
have concluded that 90% of Iranian
youngsters support the Islamic regime
and consider themselves as as
religious?" Okay, see, let me address
the second part first. Major foreign
polls have concluded something about the
population of Iran. Did they come into
Iran? They come to Iran and and do a
poll in the on the streets of Iran. No.
So how have they concluded this? By by
polling a sample of what? Expats. They
don't represent the actual Iranian
population.
So my question is what was the
methodology the statistical methodology
used in these polls which I I am pretty
sure will be very questionable. Anyhow
that's the second part. But the first
part is is regime change possible in
Iran? It is possible. it is possible. um
all you have to do well it's not it's
not some small all it's a huge all you
if if
the US or or Israel or a combination of
these two nations they significantly
degrade Iran's military capabilities and
make the government very vulnerable in
in the sense that they cannot properly
control their population then it's very
easy to create revolts
see Israel for example give me I'll give
you an example Israel Israel
consistently ly supports Azarbaijan in
its conflict against Armenia. Why is
that?
So Iran, so Israel supports Azarbaijan
while India supports Armenia. We are on
opposing sides, right? So why does
Israel support Azharbaijan? Because
there's a significant
Azari population in Iran in the east
Azarbaijan province, right? And Israel
would like to someday incite a revolt
there against the Iranian government. So
if the government becomes weak, if the
government seems uh shaky, then you
could see potentially revolts rising up
in Iran because half the population of
Iran is non-persion.
So there are multiple ways in which this
can be done. If if they assassinate
various key figures in the government in
military that also will make the
government very unstable. There are so
many ways in which this can be done.
It's not easy but it's possible. So
regime change is indeed possible in
Iran. And then then if it's true that
90% of Iranians support the Islamic
regime, then that could be a factor
which would make regime change more
difficult. So multiple factors come into
this. But I'm not sure about these
foreign polls. I'm not sure what method
methodology they use to conclude
whatever they've concluded.
Uh Shivan says Shivanch Shivanch says do
you think that for an alien looking from
the top Russia would be the most
powerful nation on the planet since it
has the most land and hence most
resources.
uh aliens are sup look if aliens
extraterrestrials can come all the way
to the earth it means they are way more
intelligent than us right like if if the
highest IQ a human can have is
hypothetically 200 then maybe an alien
has an IQ average IQ of 2,000 or 20,000.
So for them to be looking at us and
examining us is essentially like us
examining a population of ants.
Okay. So that's how they will look at it
like a bunch of ants and different
colonies of ants who seem to be who seem
to be competing for resources and they
seem to have some dis colonies have
that. So how do humans conclude which
ant species is is more powerful?
One factor you will see is how big is
the colony? How much territory do they
control and resources? Secondly, what
are the weapons they have which is like
uh how you know the pinsers that they
have and whatnot. What kind of chemical
uh secretions do they have and all so
on. So yeah, if you look if you think of
it from that perspective, they may
perhaps conclude that, you know, Russia
has the biggest land resources, but the
Americans are far more poisonous
possibly than Russia. But the Russians
have the biggest claws or or mandibles
because they have more nuclear weapons
than the Americans.
So for an alien looking from top, I
think Russia and the US would be the
most powerful nations. Yeah, maybe
Russia perhaps, maybe. But if they then
look at the details and they will say
that the Americans those ants they
control much of the world's uh trade
routes and all that. So maybe that makes
them more powerful. So maybe they will
conclude that Russia
yeah aliens are obviously more
intelligent than us. So they will
conclude the US is is more powerful most
likely. All right. But very interesting
thought experiment you're giving here.
Very in very interesting Gdankan
experiment.
And that's about it. Young Sonic, thank
you so much sir. Ma'am, thank you so
much. Appreciate that. So, we are at the
end of Okay, there's one more question.
So, please uh stop asking questions
because I'm going to end after this one.
Rajat Chhatraji says some stats are
saying that Russia lost 1 million
soldiers in the war so far. As per the
western media, as per my as per my
analysis, what's the real number of pe
soldiers they've lost? I have absolutely
no way of telling how many soldiers
Russia has lost because I don't have my
ears, my eyes and ears on the ground in
Ukraine or in Russia. But with that
being said, let me say this. You can't
trust the western media. The western,
look, media is just propaganda today.
Media in the past theoretically it was
supposed to report the truth but today
media is the most powerful source of
propaganda of create of of creating
narratives of perpetuating false
narratives. So the western media we know
it lies they consistently light up lie
about us. So obviously they're also
lying about this matter.
Um they have been saying Russia has been
losing millions of soldiers for since
2022. I remember Ursula from their lean
she once said this and and it came out
all over Twitter that the video that
Ukraine had lost I don't know 300,000 or
something soldiers and then the video
was deleted but it's never deleted right
so the truth is that Ukraine has lost
far more soldiers most likely most
likely I don't know if Russia has lost 1
million soldiers if that was the case
then Mr. Putin's popularity would not
would certainly go down if I mean 1
million is a large number for even even
India.
1 million is a huge number even for
India. So I think you have to take these
claims with more than a grain of salt.
Maybe a spoonful of salt. I don't think
Russia has lost a million soldiers.
Maybe I don't think they have even lost
as many soldiers as as Ukraine. They
definitely would have lost soldiers but
nothing like what the West is claiming.
So my perspective is that I don't know
how many soldiers either side has lost
but I don't trust the western media if
they are giving a certain number we
should maybe divide by 10 at least
divide by five at least divide by two or
whatever you want to do that's that's up
to you so my main point is I don't trust
these numbers not at all
okay that brings us to the end of
today's live stream thank you so much
everybody for all the questions I really
enjoyed this really enjoyed
And we'll keep doing this next week. So
next week we will do one live stream
about history in which I will take
questions from the comments and the
second live stream will be about
geopolitics which will be a super chat
live stream. Thank you so much and I
will see you next week. Take take care.
Keep asking questions. Keep raising your
standards and I'll see you if you choose
to tomorrow 6 p.m. All right. Good
night. Good day. Take care. Bye-bye.